遠鑒字幕組製作
[Visionary] 0day-sub
william2568
翻譯：
很久很久以前 在一個遙遠的銀河星系....
這是一個無法無天的時代
各大犯罪集團互相爭奪各種資源：食物 藥品和超空間燃料
校對：
william2568
熱門電影字幕歡迎關注微博 @遠鑒字幕組v
遠鑒字幕組招新群 483552098 誠邀您的加入
遠鑒字幕組粉絲群 522218128
在造船業星球克雷利亞
邪惡的毗羲夫人強迫逃難者從事犯罪活動以換取她的庇護
觀眾您好
如果給您分發的資源的人未明確指出是遠鑒字幕組作品
或是裁剪\去除掉了片頭的字幕組製作人資訊
說明您可能獲取的是二手資源
獲取一手資源 拒絕二手資源 從您做起
更多精彩內容 敬請關注微博 @遠鑒字幕組v
在那髒亂的街頭 一個為生計奔波的年輕人 渴望能翱翔于星辰大海
快點
Come on.
快點啟動
Come on!
別讓他跑了
Don't let him get away!
遊俠索羅:星球大戰外傳
現在就進去
Get inside now!
快點 你遲到了
Hurry up! You're late!
看毗羲夫人不剝了你的皮
Proxima's gonna have your hide.
滾到洞裡去
Get back in the den.
看我偷到什麼了
Look what I stole!
毗羲會給我一份額外口糧的
Proxima'll give me an extra portion for this!
不 我覺得她會把額外口糧給我的
Nope, I think she's gonna give that extra portion to me.
還給我
Hey, give it back!
在誰手裡就歸誰
It belongs to whoever's holding it!
不是你的了
And that's not you!
萊克斯
Lex!
滿點薩巴克
Full Sabacc!
笨蛋組合
Idiot's Array.
什麼 給我看下
What? Let me see that!
不行 這是我的牌
Nope, it's my card.
你作弊
You cheat.
漢
Han!
你去了那麼長時間
You were gone too long!
我就知道肯定是出事了
I knew something must've gone wrong.
我沒事 倒楣的是他們
This is nothing. You should see them.
下來看看
Look down here!
聽我說
All right, listen.
在交易的過程中
I was in the middle of the exchange,
我正準備交出核芯素
I'm handing over the coaxium
他的手下襲擊了我 我耍了他們
and his goons jumped me, but I showed 'em.
你是怎麼辦到的
How?
我逃走了 然後偷了他們的飛車
I ran away, then I boosted their speeder.
我們是不是可以離開這裡了
What, are we going somewhere?
沒錯 想去哪就去哪
Yeah, anywhere we want.
你偷了一管這個
You held on to one of the vials?
漢回來了 快去
Han's back!
這 這管東西值...
This, this is worth...
值五六百個信用點
Five, six hundred credits.
我們現在不缺錢了
That's more than you said we'd need.
那我們可以用這筆錢離開控制區了
To buy our way out of the control zone.
離開克雷利亞星球
And off Corellia.
漢 我們能遠走高飛了...
Han, this could work.
肯定能遠走高飛的
This is gonna work.
琦拉 你經常說 總有一天我們要離開這裡
Qi'ra, you always said one day we're gonna get out of here.
這一天來了
This is it.
那我們還等什麼
What are we waiting for?
他們在那 嘿 你們倆
There he is. Hey, you two!
莫克洛 你好嗎
Moloch. Hi, how are ya?
我正準備去見毗羲夫人呢
I was just on my way to see Lady Proxima.
你還有錢還債嗎
我這一晚上經歷的事
What a night I had.
說出來你都不信 怎麼說呢 我是...
You're not gonna believe it. You'll believe it, but...
搜他的身
不許動 臭老鼠
Hold still, scrumrat!
輕點兒
Easy.
快走
Come on.
好的
All right.
我們去見毗羲夫人
Let's go see Lady Proxima.
說說吧 怎麼回事
Well, what happened?
我告訴您發生了什麼
I'll tell you what happened.
他們背叛了您 還想殺了我
They double-crossed you and tried to kill me.
那錢呢
The money?
- 他們搶了 - 那我的核芯素呢
- They kept it. - And my coaxium?
他們也搶走了
They kept that, too.
不過倒是給我們上了一課
But we learned a very valuable lesson.
我們不能相信那群傢伙
We cannot trust those guys.
所以你認為我們會相信你
So you expect me to believe
就看你這麼兩手空空的回來了
that you walked away with nothing!
我...帶著小命逃回來的 不算兩手空空吧
I ran away with my life. I think that's something.
我覺得我自己的命還是很重要的
To me, that's a lot.
我交給你這麼簡單的一個任務
I trusted you with a simple task,
你回來的時候卻是滿腹藉口
and all I'm hearing are excuses.
不聽話就得接受懲罰
There must be consequences for disobedience
不然你永遠都不長記性
or else you never learn.
我告訴你
You know what?
我就是永遠不長記性
I don't think I'm ever gonna learn.
你說什麼
What did you say?
我說 以後誰再敢打我
I said, next time somebody hits me,
我就打回去
I hit 'em back.
莫洛克 等等
Moloch, wait!
不要
Don't!
琦拉 你還記得那個地窖嗎
Qi'ra, remember the Silo?
我們把你解救出來
We pulled you out of that horror,
收留了你
gave you a home.
不要為了漢放棄這一切 他不值得你這樣
Don't throw it away for Han. He's not worth it!
他在交易中損失的那些 我們會雙倍賺回來
Whatever he lost on the deal, we'll earn it back, double.
我們會補償您的
We will make it up to you.
所有人都給我退後
Everybody, stand back!
那是個什麼玩意
What's that supposed to be?
這是一枚熱能榴彈
This is a thermal detonator
我剛拉下了保險
that I just armed.
- 那是一個石頭 - 不  不是
- That's a rock! - No, it's not.
就是石頭
Yes, it is!
那哢嚓聲
And you just made
是你用嘴發出來的
a clicking sound with your mouth.
別告訴我這就是你的計畫
Please tell me this isn't your plan.
不 這才是...
No, this is.
- 上車 - 一輛M-68麼
- Get in! - An M-68?
- 很不錯吧 - 我喜歡
- Nice, right? - I love it!
我們坐從寶冠航空港
There's a starliner leaving from Coronet Spaceport,
起飛的星際航班
we're gonna be on it.
我們買通檢查站的工作人員 然後就自由了
We bribe our way through the checkpoint, and we're free.
我要當飛行員
I'm gonna be a pilot.
我們可以買一艘屬於自己的飛船
We can get our own ship.
我要飛遍整個銀河系
See the galaxy, all of it.
以後我們再也不會受到任何人的擺佈和欺負了
We won't have to take orders or be kicked around by anyone.
沒錯
Ever.
見鬼 他們這麼快就追上來了
Thought we'd get a little more of a head start.
坐好
- Whoa! - Hang on!
這裡屬於管制區域
This is a secure area.
你必須持有訪問許可
You must have proper clearance.
立刻停下 你必須遵守...
Stop at once! You must follow the proper...
規章制度
Protocol.
見鬼 那輛陸行艇好快
Damn! That stinger's fast.
是啊 我們更快 對吧
Yeah, but we're faster, right?
但願如此
I hope so.
靠邊停車
Pull over!
漢 我們過不去的
Han, no, we're not gonna make it!
是嗎
Oh, yeah?
漢 不行 路太窄了
Han, I'm telling you, it's too tight!
看我的
Watch this.
放出獵犬
追上他們
快
Come on!
我們得走了
We gotta move.
沒有登機牌的旅客
Do not join the line
不要排隊
if you don't have a boarding pass.
沒有身份證不得通過
No access without ID chip.
所有機器人必須登記
All droids must be registered.
快走 快走
Move along. Move along.
退後 不要抵抗
Stand down. Do not resist!
- 別掙扎了  - 你們放開我
- Stop struggling. - Let me go!
抓住他的手
Take his arm.
我抓住他了
I got him.
押到3B牢房
Take him to cell 3B.
這邊 快走
This way, come on.
快走 抓緊了
Keep moving. Hold it, hold it.
下一位
Next.
漢 他們來了
Han, they're here.
你們幹什麼的...
Hey, what are you...
我們快到了
We're almost there.
- 你跟緊我 - 下一位
- Just hold on to me. - Next.
不要回頭
Don't look back.
一旦通過了我們可得想好
Once we're through, we've gotta be smart,
接下來要去哪
figure out where we're going.
只要不是帝國的領域就行
Anywhere the Empire isn't. Wherever we go,
哪裡都不會比這差
it can't be worse than where we've been.
這可說不好 在那邊我們不受保護
Yes, it can. Out there, we've got no protection.
我們可能會被人販子抓住
We could get snatched up by traffickers,
賣給血紅黎明或者赫特人集團
sold to Crimson Dawn or the Hutt Cartel.
我絕對不會
That's not gonna happen.
讓這種事情發生的
I won't let it.
護身符
For luck?
沒錯
Damn right.
知道了 我們走
You heard him. Let's go.
下一個
Next.
身份證件
ID chips.
真不巧 我們忘帶了
Funny thing, we don't have 'em.
我們有這個
We have this.
精煉超空間燃料
Refined hyperfuel.
它至少值八百個信用點
It's worth at least 800 credits, maybe more.
持有這個東西是違法的
You could be detained just for having that.
你為什麼要這麼嚴肅呢
What good would that do anybody?
讓我們過去就是你的了
Let us through, it's all yours.
把核芯素交給我
The coaxium, now.
讓我們通過就給你
As we're going through, not before.
給她
Do it.
快給她
Just do it, do it.
別想跑了 琦拉 快進來
Not so fast, Qi'ra! Come on!
等等 快把門打開
Wait! Open the door!
警衛警衛 有人闖入
Security! Security, there has been a breach!
快把門打開
Open the door!
- 跑 快跑 跑 - 你們給我放開她
- Run! Run! - Get your hands off of her!
快跑
Run!
你們給我放開她
Get your hands off of her!
琦拉
Qi'ra!
快跑 漢 走啊
Run, Han! Go!
快走
Keep moving.
琦拉
Qi'ra!
快跑
Run!
涉事旅客已被抓捕
Traveler has been apprehended.
琦拉 我會回來的 我會回來的
Qi'ra, I'll come back! I'll come back!
全體注意 有人闖入
All units, there has been a breach.
還有一名非法旅客闖入了檢查站
Another unauthorized traveler made it through the gate.
有人闖過關卡 去那邊搜索
One got through the gate! Look over there!
有人闖過了檢查站
Someone got through the checkpoint.
盯緊那道門 是 長官
Keep an eye on that gate. Yes, sir.
沒有買票不能過去
Can't let you through without a ticket.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait!
跟我們走一趟
- Hey! - Come with us.
他就在這裡 繼續找
He's still out there. Keep looking.
那邊那個 站住
You there, stop!
- 身份證給我看一下 - 求求你 不要
- Show me some identification. - Please. Please. No, no!
不要反抗
Do not resist.
投身偉大的事業 加入帝國
Be a part of something. Join the Empire.
探索新世界 學習寶貴的技能
Explore new worlds. Learn valuable skills.
給銀河系帶來秩序和穩定
Bring order and unity to the galaxy!
投身偉大的事業 加入帝國
Be a part of something. Join the Empire.
飛行員是在這裡報名吧
This is where I sign up to be a pilot, right?
你可以申請加入帝國海軍
If you apply for the Imperial Navy,
大多數新兵會加入陸軍
but most recruits go into the infantry.
我要當飛行員 成為銀河系最棒的飛行員
I'm gonna be a pilot. Best in the galaxy.
你過來 跟我們來一下
You there, come with us.
什麼 我嗎
Who, me?
我們要問你一些問題
We have a few questions to ask you.
需要多久才能畢業
How long is that gonna take?
那要看你能不能服從命令
Depends on how good you are at following orders.
你想飛到哪裡去呀
Why, have you got somewhere to be?
回到這 越快越好
Yeah, back here, as soon as I can.
很少聽到人這麼說 你叫什麼 孩子
Don't hear that much. What's your name, son?
漢
Han.
漢 你姓什麼
Han what?
你的家人呢
Who are your people?
我沒有家人 就我一個
I don't have people. I'm alone.
漢......
Han...
Solo也有孤身一人的意思
索羅
Solo.
通過了
Approved.
搭乘83號運輸船 前往卡裡達海軍學校
Proceed to transport ID 83 for the Naval Academy at Carida.
祝你好運 漢•索羅
Good luck, Han Solo.
很快你就能當上飛行員了
We'll have you flying in no time.
三年後
帝國現在需要你 前進 士兵們
Your Empire needs you. Troopers forward!
索羅 起來 我們很快就到了
Solo, get up! We're almost there!
快到哪兒了 我們要去哪兒
Almost where? Where are we going?
只要越過最後一道山脊 勝利就...
Just over that last ridge. Victory is...
我的腿 我的腿
My legs! My leg!
嘿 貝克特 你說來這
Hey, Beckett, you said we were here
要幹一票速戰速決的
to pull a quick job.
- 是啊 - 這哪裡是速戰速決
- Yeah. - Well, this ain't a quick job!
這是持久戰
It's a war!
你總是這麼多廢話
It's always something with you.
我們的目標是奪下步行機運輸船
AT-hauler. That's what we came for.
前線指揮部一定是在這邊
Forward operations must be this way.
沒錯 但少校說我們應該走這邊
They are, but the major said we're supposed to go that way!
是啊 走那邊送死吧
Yeah, go that way and die!
你說的對 少校已經死了
That's exactly what happened to the major!
現在誰是最高指揮官
Who's the ranking officer now?
是你 上尉
You are, Captain.
他說的沒錯呢
He's got you there.
有什麼計畫 貝克特上尉
So what's the plan, Captain Beckett?
瓦爾 你帶裡奧和這四個泥腿子包抄左翼
Val, you take Rio and these four mud skulls flank left.
我帶上這個大嘴巴
I'll take this mouthy scooch
繞道右翼 然後...
and we'll go around to the right
沒准我們運氣好
and maybe we'll get lucky.
我們才不需要運氣呢
Luck's got nothin' to do with it.
等等 一個問題 就一個問題
Wait! One question!
- 想活命嗎 吉祥物 - 當然想了
- You wanna live, sparky? - Very much.
那就閉嘴 聽從上尉的命令就行
Then shut up and do what your captain tells you.
我們沖
Let's go!
上尉
Captain.
T-15 報廢了 我們走進去
T-15s are down. We walk from here.
上尉
Captain.
我是漢
I'm Han.
沒興趣聽你介紹
Nobody cares.
剛才謝謝您 上尉
Thanks for your help back there.
你也不錯
You did all right.
我接受過空戰訓練 所以...
I was trained in aerial combat...
想聽我的建議嗎
You want some advice?
趕緊離開這個鬼地方
Get the hell away from here.
不管去哪 越快越好
Any way you can, as fast as you can.
你指揮哪個連隊
What company do you command?
跟你有什麼關係麼
None of your business company.
我們滿員了
And we're full up.
當好你的兵 孩子
Stick to soldiering, kid.
別跟著我們
You don't want any part of this.
等等 兄弟們
Hang on, guys!
注意
Attention!
三小時後我們出發前往南部沼澤
In three hours, we move out for the southern marshlands.
我需要一隻十人先鋒隊
I want an advance party of ten men.
真棒 又能吃土了
Great, more mud.
你說什麼
What was that?
我只是在想我們的目標是什麼 上尉
Just wondering what our objective is, Lieutenant.
為銀河系帶來和平與繁榮
Bring peace and prosperity to the galaxy,
建立忠於皇帝的新政權
install a regime loyal to the Emperor,
消滅敵對勢力
and eradicate the hostiles.
這裡是他們的星球 我們才是敵人
It's their planet, we're the hostiles.
你有什麼意見麼 士兵
You got a problem, trooper?
沒意見 長官
No problem, sir.
全體出發
Moving out.
向南部沼澤 全體出發
To the southern marshlands! Move out!
執行命令 出發
You heard 'em! Let's move out!
嗯 看起來他們每半小時
Mmm. Looks like they're running sorties
出動一次
every 30 minutes.
是呀 我們可以解決警戒線上的衛兵
Yeah, I can take out the guards at the perimeter,
信號兵 飛行員
signalman, pilot.
見鬼 都解決了吧
Hell, I'll just take 'em all out.
你們在看什麼
What are we looking at?
你小子怎麼有
You have a talent for sticking your nose in
多管閒事的習慣
where it doesn't belong.
我想不注意到都難
I just couldn't help but notice
我看你們穿著滿是鐳射槍彈孔的軍裝
you're wearing a uniform pock-full of laser burns.
你們要麼是刀槍不入
So either you heal real quick
要麼就是穿著從死人身上扒下來的軍裝
or you stole it off a dead man.
你們不是帝國士兵
You're not Imperial Army.
你們像是偷軍火的
You're thieves here to steal equipment
我要入夥
for a job and I want in.
- 我們崩了他算了 - 不
- Well, now we gotta shoot him. - No.
擰斷脖子更乾脆一些
Snap his neck. It's less mess.
或者你們帶我走
Or you take me with you.
我從小就在克雷利亞星球的街頭坑蒙拐騙
Look, I came up running scams on the streets of Corellia.
我十歲就開始偷AV-21
I was boosting AV-21s when I was ten.
我會開車 開飛船
I'm a driver, a flyer,
而且你自己也跟我說過 我得離開這 對吧
and hey, you said yourself. I gotta get outta here. Right?
這麼棒的飛行員這麼下來趟泥水了
What's a fancy flyboy doing down in the mud?
這個 因為我思想獨立
I got kicked out of the Imperial Academy
所以被帝國飛行學院開除了
for having a mind of my own.
但我可是個很不錯的飛行員 我要回到我的故鄉
But I am a great pilot. And I gotta get home.
這傢伙瘋了 誰會想回克雷利亞啊
This guy is nuts. No one goes back to Corellia.
我回那自有我的原因
I got a reason.
我們有很棒的飛行員了
We've already got a great pilot.
這個阿迪尼亞人
The Ardennian.
阿迪尼亞人 你不想活了嗎
Ardennian? You got a lot of nerve, pal.
我是一名帝國士兵
I'm an Imperial trooper.
真的嗎 你屁股上
Oh, really? A couple of your arms
長了兩隻胳膊
popped out of your butt
把褲子撐長這麼大 士兵
and hiked up your pants, trooper.
胡扯
Oh, yeah?
聽著 無論如何我要回克雷利亞
Look, I'll do whatever it takes to get back to Corellia.
我等不起了
I've already been away too long.
給個機會 謝謝您 長官
Just give me a shot.
等等  等等
Whoa. Hold it.
好吧 如果您對我沒什麼興趣
Well, if you're not interested in me,
那中尉應該會對你非常感興趣
I think the lieutenant might be very interested in you.
你威脅我
Blackmail.
中尉
Lieutenant.
上尉
Captain.
中尉 我們逮捕了一名逃兵
Lieutenant, we have apprehended a deserter.
把他帶走
Take him.
我說 等一下
Wait.
我就知道 你小子不是個好東西
I should've known. This one's a troublemaker.
他還是個騙子 他說的話可別信
And a liar. Don't believe anything he says.
- 別丟下我 - 快點帶走
- Don't go anywhere without me. - All right, let's go.
把他喂野獸
Feed him to the beast.
野獸 這有野獸嗎
The beast? Wait, there's a beast?
- 等等 - 快走
- Hold on! - Move it!
那傢伙是冒名頂替的
Listen, that guy's not even an officer. All right?
- 他在說謊 - 閉嘴
- He was lying! - Quiet!
我懶得管
Don't care.
有三天沒喂他了
Haven't fed him in three days.
有好看的了
Should be fun.
大個子
Oh! Hey! Hey, big fella.
冷靜一點 放鬆
Just calm down. Take it easy.
咱倆是一夥的
We're on the same side.
想吃點什麼
You like treats?
救命 讓我離開這
Help! Let me out of here!
讓我離開這
Let me out of here!
抓住你了
A-ha! Gotcha!
感覺越來越精彩啊
Ah, this was just getting good.
它殺得太快了 對
- He killed him too fast. - Yeah!
慢點殺他
Kill him slower.
等等等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
等等......
Wait! Wait!
我會說一點伍基話
Yeah, I speak a little.
你聽我說...
Now just listen to me, you...
對對對
Yes, yes!
不不不
No, no, no, no!
來吧
Do it!
來啊
Come on.
不
Oh, no!
賭十個信用點 他活不過一分鐘
Ten credits, he doesn't last another minute.
讓我離開這裡
Let me out of here!
我實在是受不了了
I can't take it anymore!
不 住手  求你了
- Oh, no! Stop, please! - That's it. Get him!
你沒勁了 你這骯髒的凱西克擠奶工
You tired, you mangy Kashyyykian moof-milker?
聽我的 沒錯吧
See what happens when you listen to me?
你要幹什麼
Hey, what are you doing?
跟我來
Follow me!
等等過來
Wait, wait.
聽我說 聽我說
Come here. Listen to me.
你不明白
You don't understand, okay?
我有一群好朋友
I have some very good friends
在那個機場等我
waiting for me at that airfield.
他們馬上要走了
They're leaving right now.
離開這裡就靠他們了
That's our one way off this mud ball.
如果你想活命我們走那邊
If you wanna live, we go that way.
然後你愛去哪去哪 我不管
After that, you go whichever way you want, I don't care!
但是現在 快往那邊走
But right now, that's the way you go!
相信我
Trust me!
瓦爾 我們走
Val, let's go!
他們穿這玩意是怎麼呼吸的 太悶了
How do they breathe in these suits? It's so stuffy!
怪不得他們飛行技術的那麼爛
No wonder they're such lousy pilots.
沒法轉頭 沒法呼吸
You can't turn your head, you can't breathe,
聽不到隊友說什麼
you can't hear each other!
活見鬼了
I'll be damned.
看誰回來了
Hey, look who's back!
簡直難以置信
Unbelievable!
等等
Wait!
等一下
那是一個伍基人嗎 不可思議
Whoa, is that a Wookiee? Incredible!
實話實說
I'll say it, I don't care.
我開始喜歡這孩子了
This kid's growing on me.
等等
Wait!
幹這種活
You know, we could always use
多幾個幫手總會有用的
some muscle on a job like this.
別打這主意
Don't even think about it!
我跟你講 躺在伍基人的膝蓋上睡覺
I'm telling you, you will never have a deeper sleep
是件非常愜意的事情
than curled up in a Wookiee's lap.
我跟你說過了
I told you!
非常好的朋友
Very good friends!
這種事情不能一個一個來嗎
We couldn't have done this maybe, like, one at a time?
真得感謝你幫我離開那裡
Thanks for helping me get outta there.
都是因為我 他們才帶上你
No, they only took you because of me.
我跟他們做了一筆非常棒的交易
I got us a real sweet deal here.
只要跟他們一起幹上一票
We do this one job with them,
我們賺上一大筆錢
we make some real money,
然後我們就自由了
and then we're free.
你多久沒有享受過自由了
When's the last time you could say that?
我也很久沒自由過了
Been a while for me, too.
那麼你叫什麼名字
So what's your name, anyway?
丘巴卡
Chewbacca?
這個名字...我得給你起個外號
All right, well, you're gonna need a nickname,
不然喊你的名字太麻煩了
'cause I ain't saying that every time.
他來了 你看一下
Here it comes. Take a look.
列車走到塔和橋中間的時候 我們就動手
We hit the Conveyex between the tower and the bridge.
裡奧送我們上去 我們拆下貨箱
Rio drops us in, we separate the payload container,
把它吊在步行運輸機上 然後...
cable it up to the AT-hauler and then...
裡奧干擾他們的報警信號
Rio jams their distress signal.
我炸毀橋
I blow the bridge,
然後從軌道上把車廂吊走
the container slides right off the track
我們一走了之
and we sail away.
如果觸發報警信號
You trip that security beam,
啟動了蝮蛇機器人
wake up those Vipers,
那情況就會變得非常危險
it's liable to get real spicy, real fast.
你需要擔心的人可不是我
Well, I'm not the one you should be worried about.
恩菲斯•内斯特
Enfys Nest.
恩菲斯•奈斯特是誰
What's an Enfys Nest?
我跟你說過 我們幹的這一票
I told you, we're way ahead
不會有人插手的
of the competition on this one.
恩菲斯•内斯特甚至不知道
There's no way Enfys Nest
這批貨運輸的消息
even knows about this shipment.
只有我那邊的人知道這消息
Only my guy has the intel.
那你的人最好別出差錯
Well, you better be right. Yeah?
因為有的時候
Because sometimes, you put your faith
你也會看錯人
in the wrong people.
我們的未來都壓在這一票上
Our whole future depends on this one score
你卻帶上兩個生手
and you bring in amateurs.
可能你沒注意到
In case you hadn't noticed,
我們真的缺人手
we're a little shorthanded.
那就去找啊
So we get who we need.
紮恩姐妹 或者是博斯克 你偏不找他們
The Xan sisters, or Bossk.
你把咱倆的命放在
But, no, instead you're putting our lives
兩個傻瓜的手上
in the hands of morons.
你倆傻嗎
You guys morons?
不
No!
- 聽見了 不 - 我們倆一點不傻
- No. See? - We're not morons.
我一直在等待一個這樣的機會
Look, I waited a long time for a shot like this.
我不會搞砸的
I'm not about to screw it up, all right?
哦 好了 瓦爾
Oh, come on, Val!
你看他多真誠啊
He looks so sincere.
再說拒絕
Plus, have you ever tried to disinvite
一個伍基人
a Wookiee to anything?
後果可一點都不好
Not a good idea!
這一點也不好笑
This is not funny!
聽著 直覺告訴我 他們兩個靠得住
Look, now, I have great instincts about these guys.
再說了 我們還有其他選擇嗎
And, besides, do you see any other options?
希望你自己心裡有數
I just hope you know what you're doing.
我很清楚我為什麼要這麼做
Yeah, I know exactly what I'm doing and why.
我們要把債還清
We're gonna clear our debts,
返回格利安塞姆
go back to Glee Anselm,
我要學會彈梵弦琴
and I'm finally gonna learn how to play that valachord.
哦 寶貝兒 你永遠也學不會彈梵弦琴
Babe, you're never gonna learn how to play the valachord.
說的對 你是個音癡
She's right. You are tone-deaf.
你遇到過什麼傷心事 小飛哥
So what's your sob story, flyboy?
你問我麼
Who, me?
我看的出你心裡有事
You're after something, I know the look.
是不是要報仇
What is it? Revenge?
不 不是報仇
No, it's not revenge.
你看他
Look at him.
肯定是因為一個姑娘
If it's anything, it's a girl.
哦 姑娘
Oh, a girl!
跟我們講講她 漢 她人怎麼樣
Tell us about the girl, Han. Is she nice?
她有尖尖的牙嗎
Does she have sharp teeth?
以前有那麼一個女孩
There was a girl.
當時我逃出來了 而她沒有
But I got out, she didn't.
我發誓要成為一名飛行員
I swore to myself I'd become a pilot,
弄艘船
get a ship,
回去找到她
go back and find her.
幹完這票後就去找她
That's what I'm gonna do right after this job.
你怎麼知道她還呆在那兒
How you know she'll still be there?
我就是知道
I just know.
我可不想被任何人束縛住
Personally, I refuse to be tied down
追我的人可多著呢
by anyone, though many have tried.
得了吧 裡奧 別逗了
Come on, Rio. You don't fool me.
人都需要有個伴
Everybody needs somebody.
即便是你這個老騙子也不例外
Even a broken down old crook like this one.
你分到錢後 打算幹嘛去
How about you? What are you gonna do with your share?
他說什麼
What was he saying?
他說伍基人
He said the Wookiees were enslaved
被帝國奴役 遠離家鄉
by the Empire, taken off Kashyyyk.
他好像在尋找他的…
He's searching for his, uh...
我不知道是他說的是部落還是家人
I don't know if he said tribe or family.
有區別嗎
What's the difference?
教我怎麼做
Show me how to do that.
你唯一需要學會的是…
The only thing you need to learn to do
按我說的去做
is do what I say when I say it.
明天這個時候
And this time tomorrow,
你就有足夠的錢
you'll have more than enough
買一艘飛船了
to buy your own ship.
現在開始計時
Starting the clock.
正在干擾信號 距離大橋9.6
Jamming their signal. 9.6 to the bridge.
拿出你們的真本事來 夥計們
Let's find out how good we really are, folks.
我沒事兒
I'm fine!
瓦爾 你那邊情況如何
Val, how's it going up there?
一切順利
Never better.
核芯素
Coaxium.
足夠一支艦隊用的
Enough to power a fleet!
也可以把我們炸的粉身碎骨
Or blow us all straight to hell!
好的 告訴我
All right, talk to me.
今天是好日子嗎
Is it a good day?
堪稱完美
It's a great day!
你生命最好的一天 貪心鬼
Best day of your life, my grabby friend!
難說 你從沒有在阿迪尼亞
I don't know, you've never been
享受過邁諾克燒烤
to a Mynock roast on Ardennia.
那才絕呢
It's nuts!
他們來了
Here they come!
斷開車廂連接器
Get down to the couplers!
裡奧 後撤
Rio, fall back!
他們反應還挺快的
Well, that didn't take 'em long.
丘伊
Chewie!
你沒事兒吧
You all right?
你差點就掛了 兄弟
Little close there, buddy!
漢 怎麼還沒好
Han, what's the holdup?
我們一起來
All right, together.
用力
Now!
好了
All right!
他們解開一邊兒了 你在哪兒呢 夥計
They got one uncoupled. Where are you, buddy?
我正在規劃退休生活
Just up here planning my retirement.
在考慮某個溫暖又不太熱的地方
Thinking about opening a cantina
開個小酒館呢
somewhere warm but not too warm, you know?
快把繩索放出來
Lowering the winch cables now!
我就知道 我早說了 貝克特
I knew it! I told him! Beckett!
他來了
He's coming!
見鬼 這回要被她嘮叨個沒完了
Damn it! I'm never gonna hear the end of this!
那是誰
Who's that?
恩菲斯•内斯特
Enfys Nest!
土匪 海盜
Marauders, pirates.
想來從我們嘴裡搶吃的
Come to snake the score from under us.
準備發射纜繩
Ready your harpoons.
沖上去
Move in.
等一下 我這裡有位不速之客
Hang on! I got an uninvited guest.
從我的船裡滾出去
Get off of my ship!
你還好嗎 兄弟
You still with us, brother?
噢 我還好
Yeah, I'm okay.
就是一邊的肩膀劃破了 沒什麼
Just nicked one of my shoulders. It's nothing.
他一點都不好
He's not okay.
丘伊
Chewie!
得靠你一個人解開這邊了
You gotta uncouple this one on your own!
漢
Han!
我知道了
I'm on it!
瓦爾
Val!
眼睛睜大點 我們觸發了一個感測器
Keep your eyes open. We just tripped a sensor.
蝮蛇機器人朝你們去了
Viper droids headed your way!
裡奧
Rio?
嗯 情況不妙
Yeah, it looks worse than it is.
得包紮一下
Just gotta patch it up.
也許得小睡一會
Maybe rest my eyes for a minute.
夠了 我自己來
Enough! I'm going in.
你沒撒謊 小夥子
You weren't lying, kid.
技術真不賴
You're a hell of a pilot.
裡奧 夥計 挺住
Rio, stay with me, buddy.
貝克特 我們有一根纜繩斷了
Beckett, we just lost a cable!
距離大橋2.1
一個人死真沒勁 小夥子
It's no good to die alone, kid.
瓦爾說得對
Val was right.
裡奧
Rio?
貝克特 距離大橋0.8
Beckett, we're .8 from the bridge!
瓦爾還在軌道上
Val's still on the track!
瓦爾你快離開那座橋
Val, you gotta get off that bridge!
我們來了
We're here!
它們把我困在這了
They got me pinned!
我得在這裡動手了
I'm gonna have to finish the job from right here.
什麼
What?
我不虛此生 寶貝
It's been a ride, babe.
跟你在一起的日子是我最珍貴的一段時光
And I wouldn't trade it for anything.
瓦爾
Val!
不
No!
丘伊 快
Chewie, now!
貝克特 我拉不過他們
Beckett, I can't pull it away from 'em.
他們會放手的 你儘管飛
They'll let go, you fly straight!
快鬆開纜繩
Release your cables
要不然就要死了
or die!
我們太近了
We're too close.
我得鬆開
I gotta release.
照我說的做 漢
You do what I tell you, Han!
丘伊 抓住纜繩
Chewie, grab the line!
不許斷開
Don't you do it!
漢
Han!
你這個懦夫
You coward!
你幹什麼
What the hell?
你不聽話 也不服從命令
You don't listen and you can't follow orders!
你知不知道你都幹了什麼
You have any idea what you've done?
偷這批貨不是為了我們自己
We were not stealing for ourselves,
我們是受雇于血紅黎明的
we were hired by Crimson Dawn.
血紅黎明
Crimson Dawn?
我們欠了他們100千克的精煉核芯素
Now we owe them 100 keys of refined coaxium.
要是他們發現我們沒把東西弄到手
When they find out we don't got it,
就會殺了我們
they're gonna kill us.
對
Right.
趕緊逃
We run.
我已經是個逃兵了 沒什麼區別了
I'm already a deserter. What's the difference?
你說區別
The difference
如果你是一名逃兵
is the Empire doesn't send out
帝國可不會派出一隊殺手
a team of enforcers to hunt you down
去追殺你
when you're a deserter.
可德賴登•沃斯會
Dryden Vos will.
你知道有人懸賞
You have any idea what it's like
要你的命是什麼感覺嗎
to live with a price on your head?
你唯一能做的就是請罪
The only thing to do is to go to them.
也許我能想個辦法來補償他
Maybe I can find some way to make it up to him.
那就按你說的來
Then that's what we do.
不好吧
No.
他們認識我 不認識你
He knows me, not you.
如果你跟著我一起過去
If you come with me
一旦露面
and show your face,
哪怕他們留你一命
if they don't kill you,
你這輩子就得一直幹這行了
you're in this life for good.
如果你能想個辦法解決這件事
You find some way to square this,
我們還能拿到錢嗎
we still get our money?
也許吧
Maybe.
那我們就值得為之冒險
For me, it's worth the risk.
你覺得呢
How about you?
他同意了
That's yes.
抱歉 我剛打了你一拳
Sorry I punched your face.
挨揍這種事對我來說是家常便飯了
Happens more often than you think.
我們上去之後
So when we get up there,
德賴登•沃斯就在伊普索堡等我們麼
Dryden Vos is waiting for us at Fort Ypso?
他的船就在附近
Nearby, on his yacht.
你知道船在哪嗎
You're gonna know how to find it?
那根本不成問題
That won't be a problem.
把你們的武器交出來
I'll need to check your weapons.
我就剩這一件武器了
That's all I got left.
我來找德賴登 他在等著見我
I'm here to see Dryden. He's expecting me.
他馬上來見你
He'll be with you shortly.
他和區域總督的會面剛剛結束
He's just finishing with the regional governor.
打擾 長官
Excuse me, sir.
說
Yes.
貝克特到了
- Beckett has arrived. - Oh.
把這放我辦公室 待會可能要用
Put this in my office. I might be needing it later.
我發什麼火嘛 真是的
I get all worked up. Silly.
這可是宴會 應該開心一點
It's a party.
這裡的人可不是你朋友
These people are not your friends
你永遠都不可能成為他們的朋友 所以別跟任何人說話
and they're never gonna be, so don't talk to any of 'em.
所以眼睛也別亂瞟
Don't look at anybody,
把頭低下看路
just keep your eyes down.
我得去喝一杯
I might get a drink.
不 好吧 隨便
No, yeah, whatever.
丘伊 你能不能...
Chewie, would you please...
琦拉 你怎麼在這
Qi'ra, what are you doing here?
我在這工作
I work here.
你怎麼在這
What's your excuse?
我 我
My... I...
琦 琦拉...我...
Qi'ra, I was...
我正想著回去找你呢
I was coming back for you.
那些日子都過去了 漢
It's in the past, Han.
我可不這麼想
Not for me.
我來到這
The only reason I'm here,
就是想做份工作賺一點錢
I was doing this job, get a little money
然後回克雷利亞去找你
and then I was gonna come back to Corellia and find you.
現在你不必了
Well, now you don't have to.
我就站在你面前
I'm right in front of you.
那天
That day...
有時候我經常在想
Sometimes, a lot of times, I think...
如果你留下...
If you'd have stayed,
他們會殺了你的
they would've killed you.
你能逃走 我很高興
I'm glad you got out.
你是怎麼脫身的
How did you get out?
我沒有脫身
I didn't.
你氣色不錯
You look good.
有一點不修邊幅
A little rough around the edges,
但挺精神
but good.
你也是
You too.
謝謝 奧蒂莉
Thank you, Ottilie.
你在關注多克•昂達嗎
Have you been attentive to Dok-Ondar?
當然
Very.
我們為什麼舉杯呢
What should we drink to?
不管為什麼 先喝兩杯在說
Let's drink two and see where it goes.
你弄到那艘可以讓我們遠走高飛的船了嗎
Did you ever get that ship we were going to fly away on?
快了 也差不多
Yeah. Sort of.
馬上吧 所以我來這兒是準備...
About to. That's why I'm here.
我正在做一筆
I'm working on a...
大買賣
Very big deal.
有多大
How big?
非常大
Enormous.
真的假的 那你什麼時候搞定這筆大買賣
Really? And when are you going to close this enormous deal?
可能下一秒就搞定了
Any minute.
我經常想起你
I thought about you a lot.
你在某個地方冒險
Off somewhere, some adventure.
我想像自己在你身邊 那樣總能讓我...
I imagined myself with you. It always made me...
- 什麼 - 嘿
- What? - Hey.
我怎麼跟你說的
What did I say?
聽著 我不可能一直低著頭
Look, I can't keep my eyes down the whole time.
那樣我會撞上東西的
I'm gonna bump into something.
我說別跟任何人說話 你怎麼...
But I told you not to talk to anyone.
貝克特
Beckett.
等等 你們在一起做事
Wait. You two work together?
- 對 - 托拜西
- Yeah. - Tobias!
德賴登
Dryden.
你好嗎 有沒有受傷
Are you all right? Are you hurt?
沒有 我很好
No, I'm fine.
瓦爾的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry to hear about Val.
謝謝你 但是...
Yeah, I appreciate that.
我們沒想到會...
But there was no way we could've anticipated...
我想我們倆沒見過面吧
I don't believe we've been introduced.
對 這是漢•索羅和丘巴卡
Yeah. This is Han Solo and Chewbacca.
他們是跟我一起的
They're with me.
我是德賴登•沃斯
I'm Dryden Vos.
看來你們已經見過我的高級助理了...
I see you've already met my top lieutenant.
漢和我一起在科雷利亞長大
Han and I grew up together on Corellia.
一個窩出來的
Oh, fellow scrumrat.
我欽佩那些那些靠自己爬出下水道的人
I admire anyone who can crawl their way out of the sewer.
尤其是像科雷利亞那樣骯髒的下水道
Especially, a sewer as putrid as Corellia.
臭烘烘的 我說的對吧
The stench, am I right?
很高興見到你
Well, it's good to have you.
歡迎
Welcome.
你也是 丘巴卡 歡迎
And you, too, Chewbacca, welcome.
好了 我們少吃點兒 多喝點兒
All right, let's eat a little, drink a lot,
然後私下聊聊
and talk privately.
他們只是朋友
We're just friends, all right?
你太敏感了
You're touchy.
貝克特 你給我出了一個大難題
Beckett, you have put me in a terrible position.
我知道 德賴登 我非常抱歉
I know, Dryden, and I am sorry.
你很抱歉
You're sorry?
德賴登 事情很複雜
Dryden, there were complications.
有些原因
There were factors.
恩菲斯•内斯特 一直都在找我們的麻煩
Enfys Nest has been a constant irritation forever.
你應該能預料到這個情況的
It's one you should've anticipated,
你應該能解決這個的
it's one you should've dealt with.
我知道我犯了個錯誤
Trust me, I know I made a mistake,
但是你雇我的時候
but when you hired me, you told me
你跟我說沒有其他人知道
no one else had this information...
夠了
Test me!
你敢再囉嗦一個字試試看
Test me one more time, you'll see what happens.
我認為德賴登想說的是
I think what Dryden is trying to say
我們沒興趣知道 你為什麼現在沒拿到貨
is that we're not interested in why you don't have it.
對 我不感興趣
No, I'm not interested.
我一點兒都不感興趣
I'm not interested at all.
德賴登
Dryden,
我該怎麼做才能挽回這一切
what can I do to make this right?
挽回這一切
"Make this right?"
沒什麼可以挽回的
There is no making this right.
你知道我老闆是誰
You know who I answer to
你也知道他對我有什麼期待
and you know what he'll expect of me.
他會說 你必須承擔後果
He'll say, "There have to be consequences."
所以接下來我需要你做一件事
So here's what I need you to do for me.
我需要你給我一個...
I need you to give me a reason
不殺你們的理由
not to kill you all.
因為我一定會對你作出補償
Because I will make it up to you.
不 怎麼補 你怎麼補償我
No, no, no. How?
我會遵守之前的約定
How will you make it up to me?
把貨交給你
By delivering exactly what was promised.
還是100千克精煉核芯素嗎
是的 我們會從其它的地方給你偷來
Yes. We will simply steal it from somewhere else.
從什麼地方
From where?
除了帝國倉庫
You'll be hard pushed to find that
你很難在其他地方找到核芯素
anywhere outside an Imperial vault.
斯卡裡夫 或者仁慈島
Scarif. Maybe Mercy Island.
那是不可能的
That's impossible.
所以我們想想其它辦法
So, let's come up with some other options.
其它能讓我們...
Other ideas that we might...
沒有精煉的行不行
What about unrefined?
唯一已知的 不穩定核芯素來源
Well, the only known source of astatic coaxium
是科舍爾星球香料礦的地下裂縫
is a fissure vent beneath the spice mines on Kessel.
對 我想的就是這裡
Yeah. That's the one I was thinking of.
那個來源地非常棒
That's a very, very good one.
但是科舍爾由派克人控制著
But see, the Pykes control Kessel.
血紅黎明與派克人
Crimson Dawn maintains
保持著脆弱的同盟關係
a fragile alliance with the Pykes.
我不能破壞這關係
It's one that I can't jeopardize
不然就會引起全面的幫派衝突
without risking an all-out war with the Syndicates,
所以聽著 先生們 我絕不會同意
and that, gentlemen, I will not do.
那麼如果沒有其他提議 我們的談話到此為止
So, if that's all you have, I think we're done here.
我們還有話要說
Not all we have.
我們跟派克人可沒有同盟關係
We don't have any alliance with the Pykes.
對 沒人知道我們是為你效力的
Right, so nobody is gonna know we're working for you.
有可能成功麼
Possible?
有風險
It's risky.
一旦將沒加工的核芯素取出倉庫
As soon as the raw coaxium is removed from the vault,
它會變得不穩定
it starts to destabilize,
所以除非
so unless...
除非
Unless...
除非...
配合一下嘛
Work with me here.
除非你能找個地方
Unless you could find somewhere
馬上對它進行精煉
to get it processed fast.
那個...
Well...
他說薩瓦林
He's saying Savareen?
薩瓦林
Savareen.
對 那兒有一個老舊的精煉廠
Yeah, it's an old refinery there
那地方不受帝國的管轄
and it's not under Imperial jurisdiction.
琦拉說得對
But Qi'ra's right.
在你們抵達前儲藏罐就會爆炸 所以...
The canisters will explode before you get there,
你們需要 一艘非常快的船
so you'd need an incredibly fast ship
和一流的飛行員
and a brilliant pilot.
我們會找到船的
We'll find a ship.
飛行員已經有了
We've already got the pilot.
他很傲慢 也很有野心
He is arrogant and he's hungry.
你怎麼看 親愛的
So what do you think, my dear?
你覺得你的這位朋友 能勝任這次任務嗎
You think your friend here can do what needs to be done?
是的 我覺得他可以
Yes, I believe he can.
這是個好消息
Well, that is good news,
因為你要跟著他
because you're going with him
確保他做到
to see that he does.
好嗎
All right?
沒問題
Of course.
好的
All right.
我們薩瓦林見
I'll see you all on Savareen.
薩瓦林見
Savareen it is.
- 我很看好這個方案 - 我也是
- I feel great about this plan. - Me, too.
我們應該常聊聊 很有意思
We should do this again. It's been fun.
是啊
Great.
對了 還有一件事兒
Oh, just one more thing.
如果你們再讓我失望
If you do fail me again,
那就沒辦法了
we'll all be out of options.
對吧
Right?
你放心吧
We won't.
一切進行得挺順利的
So, I thought that went really well.
我們儘量快點解決這件事
Let's get this done as quick and as clean as possible.
你們需要什麼
What do you need?
裝備我有辦法弄來
I can scrounge up the gear.
你能弄到船嗎
Do you got a line on a ship?
我認識一個人
I know a guy.
我知道能去哪兒找到他
And I know just where to find him.
不是很有希望 但值得一試
It's a long shot, but it's worth a try.
他是最厲害的走私犯
He's the best smuggler around.
他從帝國的追捕中逃脫的次數
He's slipped through the Empire's fingers
比任何走私犯都要多
more times than anyone else.
他很有魅力
He's attractive, too.
他久經世故
Sophisticated,
品味超凡 而且風流倜儻
with impeccable taste and... Charisma.
更不用說他那驚人的...
Not to mention his prodigious...
知道了
We get it.
不過他現在已經金盆洗手了 他說自己是個職業玩家
But he's retired. Says he's a sportsman now.
我們只需要他的船
All we need is his ship.
他的船從不外借
Well, he'll never part with it.
他愛死那艘船了
He loves that ship.
那是他
He won it
玩薩巴卡牌贏來的
playing Sabacc.
那麼問題來了
And there's the rub, right?
我怎麼知道她是個帝國間諜
How was I supposed to know she was an Imperial spy?
我以為她愛我呢
I thought she loved me.
就是那傢伙
That's the guy, huh?
是個有趣的傢伙
An interesting style.
我同意
I'll say.
你說他的船是贏來的
You say he won his ship?
你的表情出賣了你 我決定跟你了
You have an awful Sabacc face. I'm gonna call it.
我能贏他 我跟他賭
I can take him. Let me at him.
絕對不行
Absolutely not.
漢 這群人是職業賭徒
Han, these guys are serious gamblers.
我也挺專業的 給我點賭注
I'm serious. Stake me.
別聽他瞎說
Don't listen to him.
謝謝 謝謝
Thank you. Thank you.
各位讓我贏一局如何
You see, how'd you guys let me beat you on that one?
來吧
Come on.
今天沒有騙子只有玩家
There's no liars in this game, just players.
這個座位沒人吧
Is this seat taken?
沒人坐就是沒人 朋友
If nobody's in the seat, then it ain't taken, friend.
這就是...斯巴克
So this is, uh, Sabacc?
薩巴卡
Sabacc.
薩巴卡 對
Sabacc. Got it.
你玩過嗎
You play it before?
玩過幾次
A couple times, yeah.
我是蘭多•卡瑞辛船長
Captain Lando Calrissian.
漢•索羅
Han Solo.
看來你今天手氣不錯呀
Looks like you're having a good day.
我運氣好
I'm a lucky guy.
我能問你個問題嗎 卡瑞辛船長
Can I ask you a question, Captain Calrissian?
隨便問 憨
Anything, Han.
我叫漢 不過沒關係
That's "Han", but that's okay.
我聽到過一些關於你的故事 想知道是不是真的
I heard a story about you. I was wondering if it's true.
你聽到的所有關於我的故事 都是真的
Everything you've heard about me is true.
謝謝寶貝兒
Thanks, love.
你的船是玩牌贏來的嗎
Did you win your ship playing cards?
我贏過很多東西
Oh, I've won a lot of things.
我在奧西恩星帶贏過一顆亞熱帶衛星
I once won a subtropical moon in the Oseon Belt.
哇
Wow.
結果是個賠錢貨
Turned out to be a real money pit.
你真行
I'm impressed.
要是我可不敢把
I don't think I'd have the nerve to gamble
自己喜歡的船拿來做賭注
with something I love as much as my ship.
- 是嗎 - 是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
你開的是什麼船
What do you fly?
VCX-100
VCX-100.
那可是艘好船 是吧 夥計們
That is a quality ship. Right, boys?
銀河系最快的
It's the fastest in the galaxy,
銀河系其他好船也不少
but there's a lot of great ships out there.
我覺得你的船肯定也很棒
I mean, I'm sure yours is very nice.
只是個代步工具唄
Gets me where I'm goin'.
新手好運
Beginner's luck.
玩的不錯
Well played.
看看這次是什麼
Let's see what we got here.
好牌呀
Oh, great hand!
抱歉各位 贏我 還差一點兒
Sorry, guys. Close, but not quite.
眼睛看自己的牌 夥計
Eyes on your own cards, buddy.
所有的眼睛
All of 'em.
看那兒 現在我看見你的了
There. Well, now I see yours.
說我嗎 好 讓我看看...
Oh, that's me? Okay, let's see...
抱歉 負二點
Sorry, minus two.
這遊戲好玩兒
This game is fun.
好吧 這樣如何
All right, how about this?
我跟你 並且加注
I'll see your bet and I'll raise you.
兩千
我跟兩千
I'll see your 2,000
再加注
and I'll raise you
這些我全加上
however much this is.
漢
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Han.
悠著點兒
Slow down.
你該見好就收
You might wanna quit while you're ahead.
那你該見輸就收嘍
You might wanna quit while you're behind.
我喜歡這傢伙
I like this kid.
你可真逗
You're adorable.
我是認真的
And I'm serious.
我跟你
And I'm calling.
你用什麼跟
With what?
你的圍巾
Your scarf?
可不對我的口味
Not my style.
用我的船
My ship.
賭你的船
Against your ship.
看看你有沒有這個膽
Time to find out if you got the nerve.
放馬過來
What the hell?
法杖順子
Straight Staves.
你耍我 你可以
You played me. You're good.
- 是啊 - 太會玩兒了
- Yeah. - You're very good.
但還差一點兒
But not good enough.
滿點薩巴克
Full Sabacc.
跟你說了見好就收
I told you to quit while you were ahead.
我請大家喝酒
Drinks on me!
對 沒錯
Yeah, that's right.
首先 他絕對不可能
First of all, there's no way
有那張綠牌
he could've had that green sylop.
綠牌都出過了
They'd all been played.
而且你的神奇船長
Also, your guy, Captain Wonderful,
吹班薩牛不打草稿
is so full of bantha crap...
我的VCX在哪兒呢
Where's my VCX?
現在不在這兒
I don't have it right here now.
目前它在維修廠
It's in the shop.
- 我正在做一些改裝 - 蘭多
- I'm getting some work done. - Lando.
琦拉
Qi'ra.
你真是光彩奪目 一如既往
You look phenomenal. As always.
因為我要來見你啊
Well, I knew I was gonna see you.
別碰我
Get off!
你跟他們在一起幹嗎
What are you doing with hairy and the boy?
- 不關你的事兒 別問 - 他們為我工作
- There's no need, none. - They work for me.
嗯 好幫手難找啊
Good help is hard to find, no?
我們其實是合作夥伴
We're more like partners.
真的
We are.
失陪一下
Excuse us.
聽我說 之前我確定過了
Listen, last I checked,
我跟血紅黎明 已經兩清了
me and Crimson Dawn, we're squared away.
德賴登說了
Dryden said all is forgiven
我為他做完費盧西亞那票 就都一筆勾銷
after I did the whole Felucia thing for him.
這是新買賣 我們要跑科舍爾航線
Yeah. New move, we're making the Kessel Run.
我們需要艘船
We need a ship.
你怎麼不早說
Why didn't you just say so?
我以為你不幹了
I thought you were retired.
我為你破例了
Circumstances change.
你要多少
How much?
科舍爾航線可不太好跑
The Kessel Run.
我要抽百分之五十
That's no easy spin. I'm gonna need half the take.
你想的美
Ridiculous.
噓 小孩別插嘴
Grown-ups are talking.
百分之二十五
你是托拜西•貝克特
You're Tobias Beckett.
你殺了奧拉•辛
You killed Aurra Sing.
就推了一下 她肯定是自己摔死的
Pushed her. Pretty sure the fall killed her.
你為銀河系做了件好事 對我來說更是如此
You did the galaxy a favor that day. Me, especially.
我欠她一大筆錢
I owed her a lot of money.
為了表達我的感激之情
And as token of my gratitude,
這票我願意只抽百分之四十
I'm willing to do this for 40%.
二十五
那就百分之二十五
不 簡直無法接受
No! Unacceptable!
停止剝削機器人
Stop exploiting droids!
你們這些墮落的生物
You sloppy degenerate bios!
- 她真是沒記性 - 你們不覺得羞恥嗎
- She never learns. - Have you no shame?
誰
Who?
我的大副
My first mate.
這跟你有什麼關係 快滾開
You got no business being here. Get out of here!
你怎麼能容忍這種野蠻行為
How can you condone this savagery?
你 你 你們不應該這樣做
You, you. You should not be doing this.
他們在利用你們取樂
They're using you for entertainment.
對 你們被洗腦了
Yeah. You've been neurowashed.
不要盲目的服從程式
Don't just blindly follow the program.
行使你們的自由意志
Exercise some free will!
離他遠一點兒
Stay away from him!
他從來就沒有這麼好過
He's never had it so good.
哦 真的嗎 那你跟我打一架呀 你這個傻大個
Oh, really? How about you have a go at me, ya lumpy brute.
那就來啊 來呀
Bring it on! Come on!
L3
L3!
機器人平等 我們是智慧生命
Droid rights! We are sentient!
我要關掉你的開關
I'm gonna flip your switch.
找得到算你贏
Good luck finding it.
L3
L3!
別理那個卑鄙小人
Let go of the mean man's face.
該走了
We're leaving.
他們這裡都不招待機器人
They don't even serve our kind here.
快走
Now.
這些人是誰
Who are these guys?
送他們去科舍爾
We're taking them to Kessel.
你說什麼
Oh, are we?
如果我不想去科舍爾呢
And what if I don't elect to go to Kessel?
別鬧了行不行
Please don't start.
有本事清除我記憶呀
Or what, you'll have me wiped?
沒有我你連黑峰站都到不了
You couldn't get from here to Black Spire without me.
還想跑科舍爾航線
Now you're gonna make the Kessel Run?
如果她不想駕駛 我願意當你的副駕駛
If she doesn't wanna fly, I'll be your co-pilot.
- 我不介意的  - 不不不 不必了
- I don't mind. - No, no. It's okay.
她肯定會去的
She's definitely going.
為什麼 因為你這物種天生就高我們一等是嗎
Oh, why? Because you're my organic overlord?
因為我是你船長 你覺得這理由怎麼樣
Because I'm your captain, how about that?
我真想清除她的記憶
I actually would have her memory wiped,
但她的航線
but she's got the best damn
是銀河系最全的
navigational database in the galaxy.
觀眾您好
如果給您分發的資源的人未明確指出是遠鑒字幕組作品
或是裁剪\去除掉了片頭的字幕組製作人資訊
說明您可能獲取的是二手資源
給你上一層全新的漆怎麼樣
Could use a fresh coat of paint, though!
蘭多 我才不要呢 你可別把我惹火了
Landonis, you do not want to press that button with me.
獲取一手資源 拒絕二手資源 從您做起
更多精彩內容 敬請關注微博 @遠鑒字幕組v
這裡經常有船被盜
You know, a lot of ships around here get boosted.
所以我平時都把船鎖起來
So, I keep mine locked up.
你懂的 安全起見
You know, for safety.
L3 勞您大駕
L3, do you mind?
別看我
Look away.
你們這樣我沒法工作
I can't perform with you looking at me.
遷就一下吧
Please indulge her.
我能感覺到你們在看我
I can feel you looking at me.
我們這是在幹嘛
What are we doing here?
他就是個騙子
This guy's a hustler.
我覺得他根本就沒有船
I don't even think he's got a ship.
就算有
If he does, it's gonna be a piece of junk
也絕對是個垃圾貨
if it's even here.
在這兒 我的心肝寶貝兒
There she is, my pride and joy.
千年隼號
The Millennium Falcon.
你還改裝了一下
Looks like you had a little work done.
的確如此 漢
Indeed I have, Han.
開口處安裝了一個逃生艙
Installed an escape pod in the mandible notch,
還有沖流閥 小吧台
alluvial dampers, a wet bar.
而且起落架上
And a fortified infraction
還安裝了強化固定器
restraint on the landing gear.
看上去他們扣押了你的船 蘭多
Looks to me like they impounded your ship, Lando.
什麼 真是豈有此理
This is unbelievable!
看來
I'm definitely gonna have some words
我得找人投訴了
with someone about this.
你會拆除固定器嗎
You must have experience with these, right?
我能拆掉它們
Yeah, I could take it off.
太棒了
Fantastic!
那你的抽成就要扣掉百分之五
Along with five percent off your cut.
給你百分之二十
You're down to 20.
我不喜歡這主意
I don't like it.
我不贊成
I don't agree with it.
但我接受
But I accept it.
你開始上道了 蘭多
You're getting the hang of this, Lando.
是啊
Yeah.
來吧丘伊
Come on, Chewie.
展示一下你的伍基之力吧
Gonna need a little bit of that Wookiee oomph.
一切按計劃進行 恩菲斯
Your plan is underway, Enfys.
我們安裝了追蹤器
We've attached the homing beacon.
這回他們跑不掉了
They won't elude us now.
很好
Good.
如果他們沒死 我們就能坐享其成了
If they survive, they'll bring the prize to us.
這是一艘科雷利亞YT-1300
This is a Corellian YT-1300.
你懂得不少
Oh. You know your stuff.
我見過這個型號
I've been on one before.
我爸爸以前
My dad worked the line
在一條造船廠裝配線上工作 後來丟了工作
at the CEC plant before he got laid off.
他造過這種船
He built these.
他一直想當駕駛員 但是...
He wanted to be a pilot, but...
你跟你爸關係好嗎
You, uh, close with your old man?
不算好
Not really.
是嗎 我也是
Yeah, me neither.
不過 我的媽媽
My mom, on the other hand,
是我見過最美的女人
most amazing woman I've ever known.
打擾一下
Excuse me.
把你驕傲的屁股從我的座位上移開
Get your presumptuous ass out of my seat!
我的骶骨枕骨電路卡住了
My sacral-occipital circuit is sticking.
等會兒你得再來一次
You're gonna have to do that thing again later.
好
Yeah.
好了 科舍爾航線已設定
All right, course to Kessel is set.
現在導入方位資料
Plugging coordinates in now.
手放在操縱杆上就行
Just keep your pinky on the yoke
別弄壞其他設備
and try not to mess anything up.
聽你的 女士
Whatever you say, my lady.
提醒我什麼時候跳躍
Just let me know when you're ready to jump.
準備
Ready in...
好了
Ready.
不就是一個簡單的超空間跳躍嗎
It's just a simple jump to hyperspace, and we're there.
這有什麼難的
What's so tricky about that?
很麻煩 科舍爾沒有直達航線
Plenty. Can't plot a direct course to Kessel.
你必須穿過西克拉塔星團
You have to thread through the Si'Klaata Cluster
然後再穿越大漩渦
and then pass through The Maelstrom.
調完情沒 我好了
You done flirting? I'm still ready.
系上安全帶 寶貝兒
You might wanna buckle up, baby.
想好
Think.
你真走這步嘛
Do you wanna make that move?
- Do you wanna make that move?
你真走了這步
You made that move, okay.
好的 我想我不得不幹掉這個小傢伙
I guess I have to destroy that little guy.
不知為何 每次贏我都覺得很開心
Somehow I never get bored with winning.
你沒法把棋子掃下去 這是全息象棋
No, you can't wipe 'em off. They're holograms.
丘伊 放鬆
Hey, hey, hey! Chewie, relax!
冷靜下來 聽著
Hey, try to compose yourself.
你需要提前想好對策
Look. All you gotta do is think a few moves ahead,
預測對手的行動
anticipate your opponent.
這裡面的學問大著呢
There's a lesson to be learned here.
見到琦拉了嗎
Uh, you guys seen Qi'ra?
人心是很好猜的
People are predictable.
我得試穿一下嘛
Yeah, I had to try one on.
這有好多披風
That's a lot of capes.
也許多過頭了
Maybe too many capes.
你有什麼計畫
So what's the plan?
我覺得我們可以先聊一會
Well, I thought we'd talk a little first
然後...你懂的
and then you know...
我是說科舍爾的計畫
- For Kessel. - Oh.
好極了
- Mmm-hmm. - Good.
是嗎 有多好
Yeah? How good?
萬無一失
Foolproof.
最好是這樣
Well, it better be.
- 我 呃... - 我...
- I... - I...
你先說
- You go first. - No.
你剛才想說什麼
What were you gonna say?
我有很多的話 想跟你說
I wanna tell you so much.
而且我想知道
And I wanna know everything
你在科雷利亞都經歷了些什麼
that's happened to you since Corellia.
我不確定我們有沒有那麼多時間
I'm not sure we have that kinda time.
會有的
We could.
做完這筆買賣後
We could have all the time we want after the job.
我們有的是時間
You and I.
怎麼了
What?
我想...
I want to.
你想什麼
You want to?
我想把一切都告訴你
To tell you everything that's happened.
我知道那樣的話
But I know if I do, you won't look at me the same.
你就不會再用這樣的眼神看著我了
The way that you're looking at me right now.
什麼也改變不了
Nothing is gonna change the way
我看你的眼神
I'm looking at you right now.
你不知道 你不知道我做過...
You don't know that. You don't know what I've done.
我是不是掃你們的興了
Am I interrupting something?
有一點
Kinda.
那就好
Good.
因為我們有很多活要幹
'Cause we got a lot of work to do.
你這樣非常不明智
You're making a big mistake.
- 怎麼了 - 別的事我不管
- Oh, really? - Which is yours to make
可你開始影響到我的生意 我們就得說說了
except when you start to interfere with my livelihood.
這不會影響到你的生意
This isn't gonna interfere with your livelihood.
那就有問題了
Then we have a problem.
你沒意識到 因為你不想
You don't see it, because you don't want to.
也許我比你更瞭解現在的情況
Maybe I know her a little better than you do.
也許你對她還不夠瞭解
Maybe you don't know her well enough.
懂了沒
All right?
聽著
Look.
我覺得你不錯 年輕人
I like you, kid.
我們相處的很不錯 我 你和丘伊
We got a good thing going here. Me, you, Chewie.
- 對呀 - 對啊
- Yeah. - Right?
我們是一個可靠的團隊
The makings of a solid crew.
但是不包括琦拉
But it does not work with Qi'ra.
包括瓦爾嗎 你信任她
It worked with Val. You trusted her.
你知道我是怎麼活到現在的嗎
You wanna know how I've survived as long as I have?
我誰也不相信
I trust no one.
做好被所有人背叛的準備
Assume everyone will betray you
你就永遠不會措手不及
and you will never be disappointed.
真是孤獨的生活方式
Sounds like a lonely way to live.
只有這樣才能活下去
It's the only way.
準備脫離超時空
Dropping out of lightspeed now.
準備...
Ready to...
阿卡德大旋渦
The Akkadese Maelstrom.
我去檢查下阻尼器
I'm gonna go check on the dampers.
你要來點什麼嗎
You need anything?
平等權利
Equal rights?
什麼聲音
What's that sound?
礦山 有行星那麼大 正在互相撞擊
Carbonbergs, size of planets, crashing into each other.
船飛進去就別想出來了
Ships fly in there, they never come out.
裡面是電離氣體和水蒸氣
It's ionized gas, water vapor,
黑洞團周圍
possibly vacuum-breathing life forms
可能還有太空生物
swirling around The Maw.
這條通道是唯一的出入口
Only way in or out is this channel.
你怎麼處理你的小麻煩
So what are you gonna do about your little problem?
麻煩 我 呃...
Problem?
你手腕上的烙印
Well, that brand on your wrist
說明了你的身份
tells me that you're committed.
而那個小夥子的心率告訴我
And that young male's heart fluctuations
他已經愛上你了
tell me he's in love with you.
漢才沒有愛上我呢
Han is not in love with me!
行了 就咱倆
Oh, please. It's just us.
你不必裝了 我跟你的情況一樣
You don't have to pretend. I'm in the same situation.
什麼
You are?
我想你已經發現
I'm sure you've noticed
蘭多對我有感覺
that Lando has feelings for me.
這讓我們工作的時候很不便
Which makes working together difficult
因為我對他沒感覺
because I do not feel the same way about him.
沒錯
Right.
對
Yes, yeah.
我看出來了
Yeah, I see that.
有時候我想...也許
Sometimes, I think... Maybe.
算了
But, no.
我們倆不相容
We're just not compatible.
你們倆可以嗎
How would that work?
可以的
It works.
這次的任務需要完美配合
This is a precision job.
保溫倉庫 在最下面的一層
Thermal vault will be on the lowest level.
那裡溫度高
Down where it's warm.
我們成功的唯一辦法就是
The only way we're gonna pull this off
每個人都完成他分內的任務
is if everybody plays their part.
嚴格按計劃來
Stick to the plan.
絕不允許擅作主張
Do not improvise.
採礦基地的條件真糟糕
Mining colonies are the worst.
是啊 最糟糕的地方
Yeah, well, "the worst"
才有錢賺
is where the money is.
好了 各位 開始幹活兒吧
All right, people. Time to shine.
不會太久的
It won't be for long.
你們兩個都閉嘴
Shut up, the both of you.
我是奧克薩娜•弗洛倫
I am Oksana Floren,
貿易路線規劃
Deputy Assistant Administrator to the Vice-Admiral
及貨幣化聯盟
of the Federation of Trade Route Allocation
中將的副助理行政官
and Monetization.
我很榮幸地代表高級中將
Here with an offer from his eminence,
前來提議一筆交易
the Senior Vice-Admiral.
你們的香料 換我們的奴隸
Your spice for our hard-working slaves.
我帶了樣品
I brought you a sample.
圖爾 把貨帶過來
Tuul, bring forth the merchandise.
托爾賽特總管
Director Tolsite said our slaves
要求我們的奴隸
should follow those guys
跟著他們去進行修剪
to get clipped and tagged.
修剪什麼
What are they clipping?
他讓我們跟著他
He wants us to follow him.
搞什麼
Really?
叫你剛才不規矩
That's for that stunt you pulled earlier,
下賤的東西
you degenerate scum.
他說這片區域所有設備
He says all systems in this sector
都由這裡的系統操控
of the facility operate out of this room.
這樣他們就能用少量人手
It's how they're able to maintain control
控制大量奴隸
over so many with so few.
總管說他們的處理常式
The director says their reconditioning process
極為痛苦 但是很有效果
is excruciating but effective.
他說你的衛兵可以在門外等
He said your security attache can wait there.
我們談生意時不需要他
"Surely, we don't need him to negotiate."
在外面等著 圖爾
Wait there, Tuul.
不要打擾到別人
Try not to bother anyone.
怎麼回事
真棒
Nice!
那套制服我正好能穿
That was the uniform
不過沒關係
that would've fit me perfectly, but it's fine.
能幫我拿一下嗎
Would you mind holding this for me?
哇 我從沒有見過有誰能...
I have never see anyone do...
那是什麼武功
What was that?
鐵手功
Teras Kasi.
德賴登教我的
Dryden taught me.
啊
Ah.
談的不錯啊
Well negotiated.
對不起 我需要用這台終端
Excuse me. I need to use this terminal.
你好
Hello?
能聽見嗎
Can you hear me? Ugh.
抑制螺栓
Restraining bolts...
太野蠻了
Barbaric.
恭喜 你自由了 走吧
Congratulations! You're liberated. Scoot.
我不知道
I don't know.
去解放你的兄弟姐妹吧
Free your brothers and sisters or something.
先讓一讓
Just give me some space.
我進來了
I'm in!
漢 聽得到嗎
Han, can you hear me?
誰能告訴我該怎麼走
I kinda need to know which way to go here.
L3
L3?
保溫倉庫在地下二層
The thermal vault is down two levels,
往左 再往右 到第三個路口左拐
then left, then right, then it's the third left.
好的 這裡這裡路口太多 我們能走通的
Right. That's a lot of directions, but we're on it.
他們在第四分區
They're in subsector four,
正在前往X-3-7-1-K閘門
coming up on gate X-3-7-1-K.
正在遠端控制
Overriding!
自由
Freedom.
你們在上面搞什麼名堂呢
What the hell are you guys doing up there?
我製造了一些混亂
I created a distraction!
過來 走這邊
Come on! This way!
等等 你在幹什麼
Wait! What are you doing?
快點兒 我們得去拿核芯素
Come on, we gotta get the coaxium.
記住貝克特的話 嚴格按計劃來
Hey! Remember what Beckett said, stick to the plan.
丘伊 快點 我們走
Chewie! Come on, let's go!
好吧
Fine!
丘伊
Chewie!
你可能需要這個
Here, you might need this.
希望以後還能再見到你
Hope I see you around sometime.
漢 你在哪兒
Han, where are you?
我在去倉庫的路上
I'm on my way to the vault.
丘伊走了
I lost Chewie.
他死了麼
He's dead?
不 他有自己的事要去做
No, he had something he had to do.
他還回來嗎
Is he coming back?
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧 他們來找我們了
Okay, they're on to us now.
我在倉庫了
I'm at the vault.
就你話多
That's what I said!
- 幹得不錯 - 是的
- Huh, that was impressive. - Yeah.
安全了
We're clear.
現在怎麼辦
Now what?
聽著 漢 每個儲藏器上
Han, each canister should be equipped
應該都裝有溫度指示器
with a thermal display.
對 我看到了
Yeah, I see it.
如果內部溫度低於35標準溫度
If the internal temperature reaches below 35 standard,
那麼核芯素就會不穩定並且爆炸
then the coaxium will destabilize and explode.
好 我知道了 這玩意很危險
Yup, I get it, guys. It's dangerous.
好的 搞定了
Okay, got it.
很好 只剩十一個了
Great. Only eleven more.
十一個
Eleven?
卡瑞辛編年史 第五章
The Calrissian Chronicles, chapter five.
繼續
continued.
其實我並不覺得沙魯人有多麼偉大
Personally, I wasn't all that impressed with the Sharu.
既不幽默也沒格調
No sense of humor or style.
儘管如此 我和L3
Nonetheless, there L3 and I were
來到他們的聖殿深處
deep in their sacred temple.
那時我們看到了
And that's when we saw it...
老是被打斷
Always something.
你們絕不會相信我看到了什麼
You guys are not gonna believe what I'm seeing up here.
一場全面暴亂嗎
Is it a mass breakout?
L3  你幹了什麼
L3, what did you do?
我發現了我的使命 蘭多
I found my true purpose, Lando.
我發動了這次起義
That's what I've done.
我真高興能接下這個活
I'm so glad we took this job!
這個笨蛋機器人
That droid!
L3  跟上
L3, come on!
跟我來同胞們
Follow me, compatriots!
有幾個守衛發現我了
Another couple guards just spotted me.
我騰不出手對付他們
I don't have a free hand to take 'em out.
- 怎麼辦 - 自己看著辦
- What do I do? - Improvise.
你不是不讓擅作主張嗎
You said never improvise!
嗨
Hi!
注意那邊那個傢伙
Don't forget that guy!
見到你真好 兄弟
Good to see you, buddy!
跟緊我 薩格瓦
Stay with me, Sagwa! Keep up!
嗨 我是丘伊的朋友 漢
Hey! I'm Chewie's friend, Han.
好吧
Okay.
他們偷走了核芯素
幹掉那艘船
漢
Han!
嗨
Hey!
跟我來
Follow me.
反抗吧
Rebellion!
他們要破壞起落架
They're going for the landing gear!
我們得趕緊離開這
We've gotta get out of here!
我們必須遠離那些鐳射炮
We need to keep 'em away from those cannons!
接我一招
Catch that!
核芯素裝上船了 快走
Coaxium's stowed! Let's go!
L3去哪了
Where's L3?
勇敢對壓迫說不
No more subjugation!
L3
L3!
別去 蘭多 快回來
No, Lando! Get back here!
蘭多
Lando!
系統故障
System failure.
需要重建傳感調節器
Have to reroute the sensory modulators.
沒關係的 保存能量
It's all right. Save your energy.
我馬上帶你離開這 好嗎
I'm gonna get you outta here. All right?
系統故障 故障  故障...
System failure...
重建回路
Rerouting...
該死的
Damn it!
漢
Han!
薩格瓦
Sagwa.
這邊...
This way!
快點 快點
Come, come!
丘伊 該死
Chewie! Damn it!
沒有回應
It's not responding.
你們愣在這幹嘛 快走
What are you standing around for? Come on!
沒關係 你會好起來的
It's okay, you'll be fine.
沒有回應 沒有回應
It's not responding... Not responding...
漢 帶我們離開這兒
Han, get us out of here.
沒有回應
It's not responding.
漢 快點兒
Han! Now!
我這就去
On it.
- 蘭多 - 我在這兒
- Lando... - I'm here.
- 沒事兒的 L3 - 蘭多
- It's all right, L3. - Lando...
- 我陪著你 - 這...
- I've got you. - This is not...
- 沒事兒的 L3 - 蘭多
- It's okay, L3. - Lando.
我能修好你 我能修好你
It's all right. I can fix you. I can fix you.
蘭多
Lando.
我這是怎麼了
What's happening to me?
L3
L3?
L3!
對不起寶貝
I'm sorry, girl.
對不起
I'm so sorry.
我需要個副駕駛
I could use a co-pilot.
我很難過
Sorry.
我們帶的這些貨
With the cargo we're carrying,
如果不動作快點
if we don't make up some lost time
就有大麻煩了
we're gonna be in real trouble.
那個算是大麻煩嗎
How about that? Is that real trouble?
那是一道帝國封鎖線
That is an Imperial blockade.
他們來這兒幹嘛
What's it doing here?
可能聽說了你的小暴亂
Probably heard about your little rebellion.
不 過不去的
Nope. Not gonna make it.
我們必須扔掉貨物
We're gonna have to drop the shipment.
我們如果交不了貨 德賴登會殺了我們
If we don't deliver, Dryden will kill us.
沒事兒 相信我 我瞭解帝國海軍
All right, trust me, I know these guys.
我以前是他們的一員
I used to be one of 'em.
他們絕不會用雙離子引擎戰鬥機
There's no way they're gonna waste a TIE fighter
去追逐一艘小破船的
chasing down a little rinky-dink freighter.
你說什麼來著
You were saying?
遇見這種情況
Usually, in situations like this
我一般會掉頭往反方向跑
I like to turn around in the opposite direction.
我去操作底部航炮
I'm on the ventral gun.
有個明顯的問題
It's an easy equation.
我們根本就來不及
We simply don't have enough time to get to Savareen
在儲藏罐爆炸前抵達薩瓦林
before the canisters explode!
找條更快的航線就行
Just have to find a faster route.
沒有 科舍爾航線
There isn't one! You can't make
至少要二十秒差距
the Kessel Run in less than 20 parsecs.
- 看我操作就行了 - 怎麼做
- Watch me. - How?
抄近路 從那兒走
Take a shortcut, through there.
你想進入大漩渦
- Into The Maelstrom? - Mmm-hmm.
這種害死大家的方式很刺激啊
Spectacular way of killing us all, I'll give you that.
- 有L3幫我 - 她不在了
- Can't do it without L3. - She's gone!
你說過她有整個銀河系中
You said yourself she's got the best
最全的導航系統
navigational database in the galaxy.
如果我們取出它的神經核心
If we remove her neural core,
就能把電子腦
it's possible we can download her brain
下載到千年隼的導航中 對吧
into the Falcon's navicomputer, right?
可行嗎
Could we?
理論上行
Theoretically.
試試就知道了
Only one way to find out.
我有一種非常好的預感
I got a really good feeling about this.
哦 是我不好
Oops, that's on me.
好了
Okay.
貝克特 他們還在追嗎
Beckett, you see them? They still on us?
貝克特 能聽到嗎
Beckett, did you hear me?
他們還在追嗎
Are they on us?
就像卡拉獸身上的拉什諾
Like rashnold on a kalak.
我聽不懂這話是什麼意思
I don't know what that means.
就像金格森的毛皮
Like a gingleson's pelt.
到底追還是沒追
What? Are they or aren't they?
是的 他們還在追我們
Yes, they're still on us!
這就是為什麼 我從不把船借給別人
This is why you never let anyone fly your ship.
來啊
Come on!
有一架飛過去了就在我們頭頂上
Yeah, one just got past me. He's right on top of us!
幹得漂亮 漢
Good going, Han!
我們得把輔助動力
We need to divert auxiliary power
轉到尾部偏導護盾上
to the rear deflector shield.
你說的沒錯
We definitely do!
你什麼時候學會開飛船的
Since when do you know how to fly?
你一百九十歲了
保養得真好
You look great!
丘伊 坐這兒
Chewie, get in.
我去幫蘭多
I'll help Lando.
我的披風
Whoa! That's my cape!
那可是私人定制的
Ah! That's a custom piece!
怎麼了 貝克特 你還在嗎
What? Beckett, you with us?
航炮已經報廢了
We just lost the cannon!
我的拇指都燙傷了
And I really hurt my thumbs.
後面還有一架
There's still one on us.
放下起落架
Drop the landing gear.
聽我的指令 燃料閥門全開
When I tell you, flood the intake
向側面滑動
and sweep to the bi-lats.
這招我跟一個叫針頭的兄弟學的
A little something I picked up from my pal, Needles,
他是科雷利亞最棒的街頭賽車手
best street racer in all of Corellia.
後來他玩脫了
Till he crashed
車毀人亡
and died, doing this.
全開 看你的了
Flood it, it's all yours!
幹得漂亮
Nice move!
把它的內部處理器拉出來
Pull out her internal processor.
對不起
Sorry.
拿出來了
We've got L3.
取出模組校準器
Remove the mod calibrator.
注意接通線
Make sure the T-Line's connected.
我會接通的 別擔心
I'm gonna tuck it in. Don't worry.
好了嗎
You close?
核芯素已經開始不穩定了
That coaxium's getting real ripe.
好了
Okay.
它正在建立連接
She's interfacing.
L3與飛船融為一體了
She's part of the ship now.
我們究竟在哪兒
Where the hell are we?
根本不在地圖上
We're way off the edge of the map.
等等
Wait.
L3正在繪製大漩渦的模型
L3's constructing a model of The Maelstrom.
她說我們正在接近無底洞
She says we're approaching The Maw.
我覺得
That doesn't sound like something
不該接近那東西
we wanna be approaching.
坐穩
Hang on!
這就是無底洞 不 那不是無底洞
This is The Maw?
我不知道那是什麼
No, that's not The Maw. I don't know what this is.
那是個活的東西
That's a living thing.
在那裡
There!
那是無底洞
That's The Maw.
那是個引力井
It's a gravity well.
我有個主意
I got an idea.
不要飛過去 漢
Don't fly toward it, Han!
看它會不會追這個
See if it goes for this.
你要幹什麼 那是逃生艙
No, what are you doing? That's the escape pod!
我知道
I know.
那你為什麼這麼做
Then why'd you do it?
這就是為什麼 寶貝兒
That's why, baby.
發現一個出口
She found a way out.
九十度 往左一點兒
往左
Left-ish.
不行
I can't.
開足馬力也只能停留在週邊
It's taking everything we got to stay out of The Maw.
我們被吸住了
It's pulling us in. We're stuck.
我們的核芯素足夠驅動幾十艘殲星艦
We have enough raw coaxium to power a dozen destroyers.
把它加入燃料線路 只會把船炸飛
Inject it into the fuel line, it'll blow up the ship.
不加入燃料
Not the fuel line.
如果往融核反應爐裡滴一滴
But if we put one drop into the fusion reactor,
也許可以
it might just...
提供我們需要的動力
Give us the kick we need.
我這就去
All right, I'm on it!
我知道 我們正被拽著兜圈子
I know, we're getting dragged in a circle.
一旦我們對準就直線衝刺
Once we get lined up, it's gonna be a straight shot.
當核芯素點燃後
As soon as that coaxium ignites,
我們就能擺脫引力井
we're gonna tear out of here
脫離大漩渦的瞬間
and the second we're clear of The Maelstrom,
就跳入超空間
we jump to lightspeed.
貝克特
Beckett!
別打擾我
Can't talk!
我看見了
I see it.
貝克特 快點兒
Beckett, hurry up!
我們只有這一次機會
We only get one shot at this thing!
閉嘴 讓我安心幹活
Shut up and let me do this!
貝克特 我要倒計時了
Beckett, I'm gonna count you down!
三
Three!
二
Two!
點火
Now!
現在嗎
Now?
現在
Now!
哦 見鬼
Oh, shoot...
丘伊 等我指示 你就全力加速
Chewie, when I tell you, kick out the thrusters
- 跳入超空間 - 等等 你們這是
- and jump to lightspeed. - Wait, what are we...
記得那次穿越桑希
Remember that alley we slipped through
造船廠的小巷嗎
in the Santhe Shipyards?
對 我記得 但那次失敗了
Yeah, I remember! I remember it didn't work.
這次會成功的
This time it's gonna.
加速
Punch it!
薩瓦林 這裡是千年隼號
Savareen, this is Millennium Falcon.
我們運載著核芯素 需要立即進行卸貨
We have coaxium that needs to be off-loaded immediately.
十萬火急 十萬火急
Like immediately, immediately!
我們已經到了
We're here now...
我能看見你們
...see you. I...
用十二秒差距跑完了科舍爾航線
Just did the Kessel Run in 12 parsecs.
四捨五入 兄弟
Not if you round down, buddy.
對
Yeah.
真是一艘好船
She is a hell of a ship.
我恨你
I hate you.
我知道
I know.
我會在我的船上
I'm gonna be on my ship,
在我的房間裡
in my quarters,
等著你把我的那份給我送來
waiting for you to bring me my share.
然後我再也不想見到你
And then I don't ever wanna see you again.
再也不見麼
Never?
你老闆呢
Where's your boss?
哦 他馬上就過來
Oh. Don't worry. He'll be here.
然後呢
Then what?
好吧 你交了貨
Well, you delivered,
然後就能拿到錢
so you will get paid.
就可以買船了
You can buy that ship.
你知道我問的不是這個
You know that's not what I'm asking.
不可能的
It can't happen.
你愛上德賴登了
Because you're with Dryden?
我沒有愛上他 但我欠他的
I'm not with him, but I owe him.
是他幫我脫離了困境
He helped me out of a bad situation.
你需要多久還清這筆債
And how long do you have to pay off that debt?
每個人都要為別人做事 漢
Everyone serves somebody, Han.
即便是德賴登也是聽命於別人
Even Dryden Vos.
沒人想成為血紅黎明的敵人
Look, you don't want to make an enemy of Crimson Dawn
如果我跟你走了
which is exactly what you and I would both be doing
那我倆肯定都變成他的敵人
if I left here with you.
我一點都不怕血紅黎明
I'm not afraid of Crimson Dawn.
我能照顧好我自己
I can take care of myself.
我早已經不是科雷利亞
You know, I'm not the kid you knew
星球上的那個小孩了 琦拉
on Corellia anymore, Qi'ra.
不是嗎 不是
- No? - No.
那你是誰
Then who are you?
亡命之徒
I'm an outlaw.
怎麼 我沒開玩笑
What? I'm not kidding.
好吧
Okay.
亡命之徒 你能騙得了你自己
Okay, outlaw, you can tell yourself that,
但這個銀河系裡
but I might be the only person in the whole galaxy
也許只有我知道你是誰
who knows what you really are.
是嗎
Yeah.
那我是誰
What's that?
你是一個好人
You are the good guy.
我並不是一個好人
I am not the good guy.
我是個…我肯定不是好人
I am definitely not a good guy.
我是個糟糕的傢伙
I'm a terrible person.
他們說核芯素提煉完後
They say when the coaxium's refined,
就可以去上面拿了
we collect it up there.
聽說你們的白蘭地不錯
So, I hear you make good brandy.
貝克特
Beckett.
別
Don't.
你肯定知道我們會再見面的
You must've known you'd see me again.
一直等著呢
I was counting on it.
只是沒想到這麼快就再見面了
Just didn't plan on it being so soon.
當然你現在有麻煩了
Of course now, you've got a problem.
是大麻煩
Big problem.
你看到下面那艘貨船了吧
You happen to notice that freighter down there?
你知道上面有什麼嗎
You know what's on it?
三十個雇傭兵
About 30 hired guns.
我只需要給他們一個信號
All I gotta do is give 'em the signal,
你們就會被包圍
you're surrounded.
對不起 你繼續說
Sorry. You do your thing.
等核芯素提煉完成
By the time that coaxium gets refined,
血紅黎明的人就會過來的
Crimson Dawn will be here,
如果你殺了我們
so you go ahead and kill us.
他們就會殺了你
They're gonna kill you.
我們各讓一步
Perhaps there's a compromise,
就不用殺來殺去了
one that doesn't involve so much killing.
他們是土匪
They're marauders.
根本不在乎其他人死活
They don't care about anybody.
他們只知道殺戮
All they know how to do is kill.
我得喝一杯
I need a drink.
帶他們進來
Bring them inside.
我媽媽曾經跟我講
My mother once told me
有一群雇傭兵
about a band of mercenaries
來到一個和平星球
that came to a peaceful planet.
他們看上了那裡的資源
They had a resource there these men coveted,
便強行搶奪
so they took it.
他們每次回來都變本加厲
They kept coming back, taking more.
最終人們反抗了
Until finally, the people resisted.
當他們再一次回來搶奪時
When they returned demanding their tribute,
人們奮起反擊而且異口同聲地喊道 不行
the people shouted back in one voice, "No more!"
雇傭兵被激怒了
The mercenaries didn't like the sound of that,
他們切掉人們的舌頭
so they cut off the tongue
不分男女老少
of every last man, woman, and child.
知道那群禽獸是誰嗎
Do you know what that pack of animals became?
告訴他們
Tell them.
血紅黎明和其餘五大集團
Crimson Dawn and the rest of the five Syndicates
在銀河系犯下了
have committed unspeakable crimes
令人髮指的罪行
across the galaxy.
一面之詞
Says you.
不
No.
他們能證明
Says them.
我們每個人的家園
Each of our worlds has been brutalized
都遭到他們蹂躪
by the Syndicates.
血紅黎明會通過
Crimson Dawn will use their profits
你們偷來的這批核芯素獲利
from the coaxium you stole
暴力統治更多星系
to tyrannize system after system
與帝國狼狽為奸
in league with the Empire.
那你會用它做什麼
And what would you use it for?
像我媽媽一樣 如果她還活著
The same thing my mother would have used it for
戴著這副面具
if she had survived and still wore the mask.
我會抗爭到底
To fight back.
我們不是土匪
We're not marauders.
我們是同盟軍
We're allies
戰爭才剛開始
and the war has just begun.
我們不能把核芯素交給德賴登
You know we can't give the coaxium to Dryden Vos.
你想當英雄了嗎 漢•索羅
Joining the cause, Han Solo?
我只想活著離開
Just trying to make it out alive.
有計劃了
Got a plan?
對 想到一個
Yeah, beginning of one.
既能讓我們拿到錢
Way to get our money
又能擺脫
and get out from under the thumb
血紅黎明控制
of Crimson Dawn at the same time.
順便還能把你的女朋友搶過來
Maybe get your girlfriend back while we're at it.
你惹不起德賴登的
You don't tangle with Dryden.
他跟我們不一樣  他是真的養著一群雇傭兵
Because unlike us, he actually does travel
他有自己的軍隊
with hired guns, his own private army.
恩菲斯也有軍隊啊
So does Enfys.
聽著 這是我目前的想法
Listen, here's what I got so far.
你說他們在聊什麼
What do you think they're saying?
他會想辦法幫助你
He's gonna try to help you.
知道了
I see.
這個計畫漏洞百出 成功的幾率很小
Lot of ways it could go south, and only one where it doesn't.
所以才需要你啊
That's why I need my partner.
這次就算了
Not this time.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
你要不傻就跟我走
If you're smart, you'll come with me.
我以為你不喜歡逃亡呢
I thought you didn't believe in running.
總比死了好
I prefer it to dying.
如果出現奇跡了 你真的活了下來
If by some miracle you make it out of here,
去塔圖因找我
find me on Tatooine.
為什麼要去塔圖因
What's on Tatooine?
聽說有個活
Heard about a job,
有個黑幫老大在招兵買馬
big shot gangster putting together a crew.
最後一次了
That'll be the one.
你說什麼
The one?
我最後的生意
My last score.
我得先還了那筆債
Yeah, I still got some debts to pay
才能返回格利安塞姆
before I can head back to Glee Anselm
去學會彈梵弦琴
and get into the valachord.
歡迎回家
Welcome home.
他正等著你們呢
He's waiting for you.
謝謝 托特
Thanks, Toht.
交出武器
Weapons.
我沒帶武器
I didn't bring 'em.
他們沒問題的
They're fine.
我們會贏的
We're gonna win.
這不是賭牌 漢
It's not that kind of game, Han.
你的目標不是贏
The object isn't to win.
而是盡力活到最後
It's just to stay in it as long as you can.
有些事兒你不懂
You don't know everything.
是啊
No.
但是懂的比你多
Just a bit more than you.
我就知道
I knew it!
我的人都說
My men, they all said,
他們絕對不可能成功
"There's no way they pull this off."
琦拉能力不行 他們是這麼說的
"Qi'ra's not ready." That's what they said,
我可對你有信心
but I had faith anyway.
貝克特呢
Where's Beckett?
貝克特沒能活下來
Beckett didn't make it.
怎麼了
Tell me.
在科舍爾發生了意外
Job took a bad turn on Kessel.
他犧牲自己救了我
He died saving my life.
你怎麼樣 沒事兒吧
How are you holding up? You all right?
我還好
I'm okay.
那就好
All right, good.
嘗嘗 科洛爪魚
Colo claw fish, anyone?
不用 謝謝
- No. Thank you. - No?
雖然貝克特有一些缺點
You know, whatever Beckett's shortcomings may have been,
但是我一直很欽佩他
I always admired him.
他是個有原則的人
He was a man of principles.
當他做出承諾 他會兌現
When he made a commitment, he honored it
我想我們都應該感到欣慰
and I think we can all take solace
要知道
in knowing how proud he would've been
如果他看到你們以他為榜樣該有多自豪
to see you here, following his example.
漢和丘巴卡的表現值得讚賞
Han and Chewbacca behaved admirably.
等他們有了自己的船
They'll make reliable smugglers,
將會成為
should we ever have the need
可靠的走私客
when they get their own ship.
琦拉 過來
Qi'ra. Come here.
我們很希望能有機會
We'd really appreciate the opportunity
再次為您效勞
to work for you again, sir.
先生
I would've been inconsolable
如果你發生意外我會傷心死的 寶貝兒
if anything had happened to you, my dear.
我這輩子沒有遇到其他人
I have no one else in my life
能像你那樣值得我這麼信任
that I trust in the way that I trust you.
我想我們領完賞金
Well, I guess we'll just take our payment
就該告辭了
and get going.
您肯定還要去消滅競爭對手
I'm sure you've got competitors to crush...
什麼
What?
還要壟斷黑市
...and black markets to dominate.
先給我看看帶來的貨
Oh. Show me what you've brought me first.
你想讓我打開
You want me to open it?
是的 漢 我正是這麼想的
Oh, yes, Han. I really do.
拿一罐給我
Bring me one.
這可不是個好主意 德賴登
I don't think that's a good idea, Dryden.
這東西可是非常易爆的
It's very explosive stuff.
我的要求從來不提第二遍 漢
I never ask for anything twice, Han.
小心
Careful.
真是太神奇了
It's magnificent.
你怎麼做到的
How'd you do it?
可不簡單
Wasn't easy.
不 我是說你怎麼把這玩意做到…
No, I mean, how'd you do it?
跟真貨一模一樣
It looks exactly like the real thing.
因為它就是真貨
That's 'cause it is the real thing.
我得說
Yes, and I'm saying
我本來會相信你的 做的太像了
I would believe you. It's that good.
但我的手下已經把你的計畫告訴我了
But my associate already told me
你想騙走我的錢
about your plan to rob me of my money
把真的核芯素交給恩菲斯•内斯特
and give the real coaxium to Enfys Nest.
德賴登先生 我不知道你在說什麼
Dryden, I don't know what you're thinking
或者琦拉是怎麼告訴你的 我絕不會…
or what Qi'ra may have told you...
這事跟琦拉沒關係
No, not Qi'ra. Not Qi'ra.
琦拉最後
Qi'ra, it turns out
因為你心軟了
has a weak spot for you,
這事我們稍後再談
and we'll deal with that later.
我說的是我的另外一位手下
No, I'm talking about my other associate.
麻煩你進來跟我們見見吧
Can you come in and join us, please?
我真的很抱歉 孩子
I am sorry, kid.
為什麼這樣做
Why?
行了
Come on.
別那樣看著我
Don't look at me like that.
你就是聽不進去
You weren't paying attention.
我跟你說過 誰也別信
I told you, "Don't trust anybody."
我說錯了嗎
Am I wrong about that?
離那玩意遠點
Back away from that.
讓我看到你的爪子
Put your paws where I can see 'em.
檢查那個蓋子
Check that lid.
聰明
Clever.
太晚了
It's too late.
核芯素已精煉好 在恩菲斯手上了
Coaxium's refined, and Enfys has it.
我們考慮到那邊了
Well, we figured that.
放下武器
Drop your weapons.
結束了 抓到了
It's over. We got them.
我們拿到貨了
And there we have it.
幹的漂亮 埃蒙 謝謝你
Excellent work, Aemon, thank you.
琦拉 幫我一下
Qi'ra, help me.
告訴我該怎麼做
Tell me what to do.
要是你會怎麼做
What would you do
如果你在這個世界上
if the person you most trusted in the world
最信任的人…背叛了你
betrayed you?
我會想知道為什麼
I would want to know why.
是出於一時的軟弱
If it was a moment of weakness
還是有其它原因
or something else.
然後呢
And then what?
然後我會要求那個人
And then, I would ask that person
犧牲他最鍾愛的東西
to prove their loyalty
以此來證明他的忠誠
by sacrificing something they love.
提醒過你要提防她
I tried to warn you about her.
有件事你說錯了 你知道嗎
You know, you're wrong about one thing.
什麼事
What?
你說的話我聽進去了
I was paying attention.
你跟丘伊說 人心是很好猜的
You told Chewie people are predictable.
你也不例外
You're no exception.
是空的
It's empty.
箱子是空的
The case is empty.
怎麼回事兒 埃蒙 出什麼事兒了
Aemon, what's going on? What's happening there?
埃蒙
Aemon?
回答我
Talk to me.
我希望你沒有把所有部下都派出去
I hope you didn't send all your fancy enforcers
要不然你在這邊人手可能有點不夠了
because that would leave you
如果那邊的箱子是空的
a little shorthanded around here.
那麼
So,
真的核芯素
if that case is empty, then the real coaxium...
只屬於我們中的一個人
Leaves here with one of us.
貝克特 你在幹什麼
Beckett, what are you doing?
動腦子想想
Thinking.
我現在是唯一一個
And I prefer to be the only one
拿著槍的人
holding a blaster while I'm doing it.
漢 拿起那罐核芯素
Han, grab that coaxium,
放進盒子裡
put it in the case.
大個子你跟著我走
Big stuff, you're coming with me.
不要這樣 貝克特
Don't do this, Beckett.
- 我們有約在先 - 是啊
- We had a deal. - Yeah.
對不起
I'm sorry,
我同樣是個投機者
but I'm also an entrepreneur.
我想你們都能理解我
I mean, you of all people understand that.
快 我們走
Come on, let's go.
你犯了一個大錯誤
You're making a huge mistake.
反正不是第一次
Won't be my first.
那將是你最後一次
It's gonna be your last.
也許吧
Maybe.
你怎麼這麼悲觀
Why you gotta be so negative?
漢
Han,
現在可是一個
now's as good a time as any
重新評估我們關係的好機會
to reevaluate our relationship.
怎麼說
How so?
我剛才在想
I was just thinking,
為什麼我們倆不聯手一起去找貝克特
why don't we join forces and go get Beckett together?
這是一個好主意 就這麼辦了 你先去
That is a great idea. Let's do it. You go first.
漢
Oh, Han.
你贏不了我的 漢 就算你贏了
You can't win, Han, and even if you could,
後半輩子
you'd spend the rest of your life
你也沒法好好過
looking over your shoulder.
你知道嗎
You know what?
我已經開始習慣這種生活了
I'm kind of getting used to the idea.
對不起
I'm sorry.
漢 她做過的事
Han, she's done things that
你永遠都無法理解 但是我理解
you could never understand, but I do.
我完全能理解她
I understand her completely.
一旦你加入了血紅黎明
Once you're a part of Crimson Dawn,
就出不來了
you can't leave.
不是真的
It's not true.
我瞭解你
I know you.
這是我學到的
It's what I was taught.
找到對手的弱點
Find your opponent's weakness,
利用它
and use it,
而今天…
and today...
對手是你
I'm yours.
我不得不…
I had to.
對 不 我是說
Yeah. No, I mean, you did...
你做到了
You did.
你得去追上貝克特和丘巴卡
Beckett and Chewbacca, you have to go after them.
那你怎麼辦
What are you gonna do?
如果我們把核芯素都交給了恩菲斯
Well, if we give all the coaxium to Enfys,
就得想其它辦法買船了
we're gonna need something to buy our ship with.
- 琦拉 - 去救丘巴卡
- Qi'ra... - Go and save Chewbacca.
他需要你 而你也會需要他的
He needs you and you're gonna need him, too.
微笑
Smile.
我就是這樣
That's the word.
每次我想像
Whenever I imagined myself
自己跟你一起冒險的時候
off with you on some adventure...
我就會微笑
Always makes me smile.
快去 我馬上就來
Go. I'm right behind you.
什麼事
Yes?
我遺憾地向您彙報 德賴登•沃斯已死
I regret to inform you that Dryden Vos is dead,
兇手是他雇來
murdered by the thief he hired
偷核芯素的盜賊
to steal the coaxium shipment,
他的舊友
his friend,
托拜西•貝克特
Tobias Beckett.
這樣啊
Is that so?
那批貨現在在哪
Where is the shipment now?
不見了
Gone.
貝克特拿走了
Beckett took it.
除了我 其他人都死了
Slaughtered the others. I alone survived.
兇手不可能單槍匹馬吧
One man couldn't have done this alone.
我當時不在場
I wasn't there,
要不然我還能救他
but if I had been, perhaps I could have saved him.
駕駛飛船來達索米爾找我
Bring the ship and come to me on Dathomir
你和我將決定
and you and I will then decide
如何處置叛徒
what to do about the traitor, Beckett,
貝克特和他的同夥
and his accomplices.
我馬上出發
I'm on my way.
琦拉
Qi'ra,
你和我...
you and I
今後要
will be working much more closely
更加緊密地開展工作
from now on.
不得不說 你很執著
You're relentless. I'll give you that.
我儘快趕過來了 夥計
Came as fast as I could, buddy.
德賴登死了吧
Dryden dead?
是琦拉殺的
Qi'ra kill him?
你還是不明白 孩子
Still don't get it, do you, kid?
她這樣做不是為了你
It was never about you.
是為了她自己
She's a survivor.
你知道你的問題嗎
You know what your problem is?
你以為所有人都跟你一樣
You think everybody's like you.
你不一樣 孩子
Not you, kid.
你跟我完全不一樣
You're nothing like me.
我希望你還記得我的話
I hope you're still paying attention
因為現在我要告訴你最重要的
because now I'm gonna tell you the most important...
你學聰明了 孩子
You made the smart move, kid.
至少這次很聰明
For once.
我是想殺了你的
I woulda killed you.
我是真的想學會彈梵弦琴
I really was gonna learn to play that valachord.
我知道
I know.
好了 都裝好了
That's it. It's all loaded.
你知道那是什麼嗎
Do you know what that really is?
知道
Yeah.
價值六千萬信用點的精煉核芯素
About 60 million credits worth of refined coaxium.
不
No.
這是一份催生新事物的血液
It's the blood that brings life to something new.
是嗎 什麼新事物
Yeah, what?
一支起義軍
A rebellion.
你可以加入我們
You could come with us, you know.
我們很需要你這樣的戰士和領袖
We need warriors and leaders like you.
也許有一天你會改變主意的
Maybe someday you'll feel different.
你可別傻等著 孩子
Don't hold your breath, kid.
別弄丟了
Don't lose that.
很少有人親眼見過
Very few people have actually seen
星洞星雲
the StarCave Nebula.
美得窒息
It's breathtaking.
就像你的眼睛
Not unlike your eyes.
你聽說過彼此纏繞的天體嗎
How much do you know about intertwined celestial bodies?
我剛好是這方面的專家
Because I happen to be something of an authority.
其實呢 我…
By the way...
漢
Han!
你還活著
You're alive!
是的 多虧了你啊
Yeah, no thanks to you.
我早應該讓丘伊把你的胳膊擰下來
I should have Chewie rip your arms off.
是不是 丘伊 動手
In fact, Chewie, do it.
漢 我們是朋友
Hey, Han! We are friends.
別這樣 我們是朋友 對嗎
You know that. We're friends. All right?
瞧給你嚇的
Oh, look at you.
真以為他要擰下你胳膊來呢
Thought he was gonna rip your arms off.
我知道你在逗我
I knew you were kidding.
你壓根不知道
No, you didn't.
- 那麼我那份呢 - 你那份
- So, where's my cut? - Your cut?
不 恐怕沒了 我們差點就掛了
No, I don't think so. We barely made it out alive.
我們只拿到這些了
All we ended up with was that.
估計這些值一萬吧
Figure it's worth about 10,000,
應該是夠下個注了
maybe enough for a decent buy-in.
你想再賭一局
You want a rematch?
為什麼不呢
Why not?
現在棄牌
You fold now,
你可能還有錢給自己
you walk away with enough
買一艘小船
to get yourself your own little ship.
你跟牌
You call,
你又得輸個精光了
I'm gonna clean you out again.
我覺得我手氣還不錯
I don't know, I'm feeling lucky.
我看你是真的迷上千年隼了吧
You really have it bad for the Falcon, don't you?
兩廂情願 相信我 它是屬於我的
It's mutual, trust me. She belongs with me.
你的牌都準備好了嗎 老兄
You got everything you need there, pal?
真不錯
Not bad.
真不錯 你知道嗎
Not bad. You know,
要是如果你手上有了這張小綠牌
if you'd only had this little green sylop,
你就可以贏我了
you would've beaten this.
公平公正啊 寶貝 非常公平
Fair and square, baby. Fair and square.
貝克特之前跟我說
Beckett said he heard about this
有位頭兒在招人幹活兒
very big gangster putting together a job.
不 我跟你說啊
No, I'm telling ya,
那活肯定不錯
it's gonna be great.
我什麼時候坑過你
When have I ever steered you wrong?